<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-03-12T21:39:15-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Creative Hudson Valley</title><entry><title type="html">Sloop Clearwater</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/sloop-clearwater/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sloop Clearwater" /><published>2020-09-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/sloop-clearwater</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/sloop-clearwater/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="hello-who-are-you-tell-us-about-yourself-what-are-you-passionate-about-what-do-you-enjoy-doing">Hello! Who are you? Tell us about yourself. What are you passionate about? What do you enjoy doing?</h2>

<p>I’m the Hudson River Sloop Clearwater, a 51 year old replica of sailboats common on the river back in the 19th century. The Hudson was the New York Thruway then, and my ancestors were the 18 wheelers of that time. Today my cargo is people — thousands each year, mostly schoolchildren, who gain a new appreciation for the river from my decks. I love the look of determination on their faces as they pull up my three thousand pounds of sail and spar or shout in amazement as my nets reveal the catch of the day — “A crab! An eel! A STURGEON!” — all carefully released after being introduced to the kids.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/sloop-clearwater-2.jpg" alt="Sloop Clearwater" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center">Photo by Tom Staudter</figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="how-did-you-discover-the-hudson-valley">How did you discover the Hudson Valley?</h2>

<p>My ancestors came over with the Dutch — they used sloops back in Holland and adapted the design to conditions on the Hudson. But myself, I came to the Hudson Valley in 1969 thanks to the imagination of Pete Seeger. The river was a mess then, and he believed that a big beautiful boat could bring people down to the Hudson and help them learn to love their river again.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/sloop-clearwater-3.jpg" alt="Sloop Clearwater" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center">Maiden voyage of the Clearwater, in 1969.</figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="walk-us-through-a-typical-day">Walk us through a typical day.</h2>

<p>What’s typical changes according to the season, but I’m busiest in spring when schools send their students to me. The first order of business each day is a salt-water bath. My crew pours brine over my decks and brushes it in – keeps my planks and frames from rotting. A yellow school bus will arrive around 9; the kids come aboard and off we go on a three hour sail. They will set and pull back my net, haul up my mainsail, push and pull on my 10-foot long tiller, and visit learning stations to explore the ecology of the Hudson. Just when pounding feet and the din of eager voices get a bit overwhelming, everyone goes silent for a few moments to listen while I rock to the music the breeze makes in my rigging, with harmonies from the water passing along my hull and solos from the gulls flying by. Soon afterwards it’s back to the dock for a lunchtime snooze, followed by another three hour sail. Once that’s done the crew pretties me up, furling my sails just so and doing some of the many maintenance tasks that keep me looking and feeling good for my 51 years. And if I’m lucky in the evening, some of my crew will sing me to sleep.</p>

<h2 id="where-do-you-do-your-best-creative-work">Where do you do your best creative work?</h2>

<p>I’d have to say during my sails through the Hudson Highlands from Newburgh Bay past West Point and Bear Mountain to Peekskill Bay. The winds there can pull some real surprises, roaring through the gap between Storm King and Breakneck Ridge or bouncing off the mountain slopes and coming at you from unexpected directions. There’s a nasty S-curve right at World’s End, the deepest spot in the whole river, that requires careful sailing, and rocky reefs to watch out for, not to mention the tidal currents and eddies that push and pull me this way and that. Yep, I need to be creative in dancing through that passage.</p>

<h2 id="how-has-the-hudson-valley-influenced-or-impacted-your-creative-work">How has the Hudson Valley influenced or impacted your creative work?</h2>

<p>My design is specifically influenced by Hudson Valley weather and topography and by the river itself. My fore and aft sloop rig — a single mast with a jib set in front of the mast and a mainsail behind — is really handy; I can maneuver easily in tight quarters like the narrow river channel approaching Albany. And what a mainsail — 3,000 square feet of sail, one of the largest single pieces of sail on the Atlantic Coast. That huge area of sail is great for catching the often gentle breezes of summer months on the river, and my mast — towering 108 feet over the water — lets me reach high with a topsail to catch light airs that might not make it down to river level. My hull is broad but not very deep; to keep me from being pushed sideways when the wind is abeam I have a centerboard instead of a deep keel. I can lower that centerboard like a fin to keep me tracking straight ahead or pull it up when entering shoal water. With the centerboard up I need only about seven feet of water to float safely above the bottom, allowing me to visit docks in the shallows common along the Hudson riverfront. When at docks, my low freeboard — the height of my deck over the water — makes it easy to load and unload cargo and board passengers.  While my design is great for sailing the Hudson, I get very nervous about heading out on the ocean; my rig and hull are not suited for the winds and waves out there.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/sloop-clearwater-4.jpg" alt="Sloop Clearwater" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center">Photo by Tom Staudter</figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="whats-surprised-you-most-about-living-and-working-in-the-hudson-valley-whats-been-challenging">What’s surprised you most about living and working in the Hudson Valley? What’s been challenging?</h2>

<p>When I first arrived I was appalled at the condition of the Hudson. Back then Governor Rockefeller called the section at Albany “one great septic tank.” I was really surprised that folks allowed it to become so polluted. That’s changed, and I’m proud of my role in making the Hudson cleaner and healthier. But it still surprises me that people who have lived in the Hudson Valley for many years know so little about the river that gives this region its name. And I worry about complacency. People generally realize that the river is cleaner, but aren’t aware that threats remain: PCBs left in place after GE’s cleanup, aging sewage treatment infrastructure and overflows, and sea-level rise due to climate change. That last challenge is huge. Many people don’t realize that — as an arm of the sea, an estuary, as far as Troy — the Hudson is pretty much at sea level. Over the twentieth century, sea level at the Battery in Manhattan rose a full foot, and since then sea level there has been rising at a faster rate. That rise in sea level is felt up the Hudson. That means that in the future it won’t take a storm as powerful as Irene or Sandy to wreak havoc along the river. And that said, scientists have recently shown that — as predicted — global warming has made hurricanes stronger.</p>

<h2 id="what-do-you-hope-to-see-for-the-hudson-valley-in-the-next-five-years">What do you hope to see for the Hudson Valley in the next five years?</h2>

<p>I’m encouraged by actions taken in communities like Kingston, my home port. After Irene and Sandy caused severe flooding in the Rondout District there, the city became a Climate Smart Community and established an action plan to address ways of adapting to climate change. Kingston is not alone; dozens more Hudson Valley communities realize that climate change is real and happening now, and are taking action to adapt to change and reduce their carbon footprint. I also see hope in the $3 billion Restore Mother Nature Bond Act, the largest environmental bond act in State history, that will go before voters this fall. Given historically low interest rates and an urgent need to invest in our infrastructure, it could give a big boost to the fight against climate change.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/sloop-clearwater-5.jpg" alt="Sloop Clearwater" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="are-you-part-of-any-local-groups-or-communities-youd-like-to-mention">Are you part of any local groups or communities you’d like to mention?</h2>

<p>I wouldn’t be able to fulfill my role as the “flagship of the environmental movement” if it weren’t for the thousands of Clearwater members here in the valley and further away that keep me sailing. Their financial contributions are essential, but their help goes beyond that. Hundreds come aboard each year as weekly volunteer crew, helping to sail and care for me as well as teaching during education sails. Hundreds more help out at riverfront festivals, picking up litter, baking strawberry shortcake, and spreading the word about ways to protect the river. And I should give a big shout out to some of my buddies out on the Hudson — the Beacon Sloop Club’s ferry sloop <em>Woody Guthrie</em>, Riverkeeper’s patrol boat the <em>R. Ian Fletcher</em>, and the Hudson River Maritime Museum’s <em>Solaris</em>, the only solar-powered boat operating on the Hudson, as well as to Scenic Hudson for creating access points for folks eager to put kayaks and canoes out its waters. Kudos also to the <a href="https://www.dec.ny.gov/lands/4920.html">Hudson River Estuary Program</a> in New York State’s Department of Environmental Conservation for their work in helping people enjoy, protect, and revitalize the Hudson.</p>

<h2 id="anything-you-want-to-plug-or-promote">Anything you want to plug or promote?</h2>

<p>You know, when one gets to be as old as I am, there are aches and pains that need to be addressed. I’m no spring chicken. So this fall I’ll be having a major checkup and some surgery as part of a long-term plan to keep me healthy for many years to come. Shipwrights will be inspecting my mast and forward part of the hull, repairing and replacing pieces as necessary. I don’t have health insurance, so I’ll be depending on the generosity of people who care about me and the river. If you are among them, please visit <a href="http://www.clearwater.org">www.clearwater.org</a> to donate to this project.</p>

<p><em>Written by Clearwater board president Steve Stanne</em>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Community" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! Who are you? Tell us about yourself. What are you passionate about? What do you enjoy doing?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dana Jones, Founder of Accessadoor</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/dana-jones-founder-of-accessadoor/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dana Jones, Founder of Accessadoor" /><published>2020-08-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/dana-jones-founder-of-accessadoor</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/dana-jones-founder-of-accessadoor/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="hello-who-are-you-tell-us-about-yourself-what-are-you-passionate-about-what-do-you-enjoy-doing">Hello! Who are you? Tell us about yourself. What are you passionate about? What do you enjoy doing?</h2>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/dana-jones-founder-of-accessadoor-1.jpg" alt="Dana Jones, Founder of Accessadoor" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Hi! My name is Dana Jones and I am 22 years old. I’m an entrepreneur, dog lover and recent graduate of Marist College where I earned my Bachelor’s degree in Business Administration with a concentration in Entrepreneurship, previously earning my Associates degree from Dutchess Community College in Business Administration.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/dana-jones-founder-of-accessadoor-2.jpg" alt="Dana Jones, Founder of Accessadoor" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>I’m passionate about increasing accessibility for those with different abilities, which ultimately led to me founding <a href="https://www.accessadoor.com/">Accessadoor, LLC</a>. After just starting college, I was struggling to travel from building to building to get to my classes because doors were extremely difficult for me to open independently. The standard ADA door technology didn’t work for me because the buttons were often out of reach or too hard to push, so I often have to wait for others to help me. One day I was stuck in a building because there was no one around to help, so I had to use my phone to text a friend to come let me out. That was the moment where I realized, if I could use my phone to have someone help me, why can’t I just use my phone to open the door? That led to the development of our smartphone application and compatible device that allows users to open accessible doors from their phone verses hitting the manual button.</p>

<p>When I was 18 months old I was diagnosed with Spinal Muscular Atrophy (SMA), which limits my physical strength. I’ve always had to be inventive and creative to accomplish daily tasks and I think that has lent to my love for entrepreneurship. Now that we are approaching the beta testing phase, our device and app will soon be available to all.</p>

<p>In my free time I love hanging out with my dogs, Tanner and Sky, who are both rescues in addition to spending time with friends and family.</p>

<h2 id="how-did-you-discover-the-hudson-valley">How did you discover the Hudson Valley?</h2>

<p>Well I didn’t really have to look far to find the Hudson Valley. I was born and raised right here in Poughkeepsie. There are so many great opportunities here and the Valley has so many things to do. You can go hiking, explore the food scene, and go to one of many local breweries with each one having a unique atmosphere. I don’t ever plan on leaving this region.</p>

<h2 id="walk-us-through-a-typical-day">Walk us through a typical day.</h2>

<p>I normally start my days off pretty early, although once the coronavirus hit, I might have taken advantage of sleeping in a little bit. My dogs wait outside my room every morning at around 8am where they get super excited and do circles around me when I exit my room.</p>

<p>I am not a big breakfast person, so I normally make my way to my phone and computer to catch up on whatever I missed overnight and answer any missed messages. Since our company is run remotely, I typically stay home and work on whatever is needed besides going out for meetings or doing pitches prior to everything shutting down for the virus. Along with many other businesses at this time, we are doing all our meetings via video conference or over the phone to accomplish what needs to be done.</p>

<p>Around lunch time I try to go outside when it is nice out and get some fresh air. I live close to one of the sections of the <a href="https://www.dutchessny.gov/Departments/Parks/Dutchess-Rail-Trail.htm">Dutchess County Rail Trail</a>, so it is nice to hop on and get a change of scenery. It helps clear my head so I can focus on what needs to be completed when I get back.</p>

<p>From there I normally try to wrap up whatever tasks I have to do by 5pm so I can switch back to family activities. One thing I think many entrepreneurs struggle with is work-life balance and I really try to maintain those boundaries and balance what I need to do in my work and personal life.</p>

<h2 id="do-you-have-a-go-to-coffee-or-beer-order-and-from-where">Do you have a go-to coffee or beer order, and from where?</h2>

<p>I like trying different things when I go out so I don’t really have a go-to order, but I love going to <a href="https://www.cafe40co.com/">Cafe 40 &amp; Co.</a> for meetings or <a href="https://www.kingscourtbrewingcompany.com/">King’s Court Brewing</a> in the City of Poughkeepsie to unwind and catch up with the locals.</p>

<h2 id="where-do-you-do-your-best-creative-work">Where do you do your best creative work?</h2>

<p>I do my best thinking at home at night. I often lay awake and brainstorm or have ideas hit me at 2am. You can often find a notepad and pen on my nightstand where I write all of them down. Half the time when I wake up I have no idea what many of them mean or are referring to, but the silence that night often brings lets me think more freely.</p>

<h2 id="how-has-the-hudson-valley-influenced-or-impacted-your-creative-work">How has the Hudson Valley influenced or impacted your creative work?</h2>

<p>One major influence of our work has been the <a href="https://www.thinkdifferently.net/">Think Differently</a> initiative brought about by Dutchess County Executive <a href="https://www.dutchessny.gov/Departments/County-Executive/County-Executive-Marcus-Molinaro-Biography.htm">Marc Molinaro</a>. Our line of work ultimately is geared towards increasing accessibility for those with physical limitations and different needs. Many individuals often don’t think about what life is like for those with different abilities and this initiative is opening the minds of individuals and increasing awareness for the needs of those with different abilities.</p>

<h2 id="whats-surprised-you-most-about-living-and-working-in-the-hudson-valley">What’s surprised you most about living and working in the Hudson Valley?</h2>

<p>I think the one thing that surprised me is what a diverse area it is for leisure activities, but also for running a company. There are so many resources for business owners such as <a href="https://wedcbiz.org/">WEDC</a>, <a href="https://thinkdutchess.com/">Think Dutchess</a>, the <a href="https://www.dcrcoc.org/">Dutchess County Regional Chamber of Commerce</a>, and <a href="https://www.coworkwith.co/">CO.</a> in Rhinebeck. It is great being able to connect with different individuals who have common interests, but it is even better that most people here want to help each other succeed. There are many networks that help you connect to others in your field or complimentary fields to help you progress in your career.</p>

<p>As far as living goes, it is such a great area because it is close in proximity to NYC, but you don’t have to commit to city life. I have no interest in living in the city, but it is nice to visit and tap into the available resources to improve our business without having the price tag that comes along with living there.</p>

<h2 id="what-do-you-hope-to-see-for-the-hudson-valley-in-the-next-five-years">What do you hope to see for the Hudson Valley in the next five years?</h2>

<p>It would be great to see more student-centered programs in business and leadership provided outside of the school systems to retain the students who are graduating from the local colleges. There is so much to do and see here and if people saw everything the region had to offer as far as personal and career growth, I bet many would stay here instead of moving to the city.</p>

<h2 id="why-is-it-so-important-for-establishments-to-increase-their-accessibility">Why is it so important for establishments to increase their accessibility?</h2>

<p>There are many reasons why establishments should emphasize accessibility and make sure they can accommodate individuals of all abilities, but it is especially important because everyone should have equal access. The simplest of changes such as adding a push button to the door, making sure the store layout has wide enough aisles and lowering a checkout counter can make huge differences. Everyone should be able to go on a carefree trip without having to call ahead to make sure a place is accessible. Universal design is going to play a large role in making the world more accessible and should be something all establishments should investigate.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/dana-jones-founder-of-accessadoor-3.jpg" alt="Dana Jones, Founder of Accessadoor" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="are-you-part-of-any-local-groups-or-communities-youd-like-to-mention">Are you part of any local groups or communities you’d like to mention?</h2>

<p>I serve as a <a href="https://thinkdutchess.com/digital-ambassadors/meet-our-ambassadors/">Think Dutchess Ambassador</a>!</p>

<h2 id="anything-you-want-to-plug-or-promote">Anything you want to plug or promote?</h2>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/dana-jones-founder-of-accessadoor-4.jpg" alt="Dana Jones, Founder of Accessadoor" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>We are accepting pre-orders for Accessadoor at our website <a href="http://www.accessadoor.com">www.accessadoor.com</a>. Be a part of the first group to get this life changing technology!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Business" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! Who are you? Tell us about yourself. What are you passionate about? What do you enjoy doing?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ned Sullivan of Scenic Hudson</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ned-sullivan-of-scenic-hudson/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ned Sullivan of Scenic Hudson" /><published>2020-07-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ned-sullivan-of-scenic-hudson</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ned-sullivan-of-scenic-hudson/"><![CDATA[<p>If you’ve been to a park in the Hudson Valley, there’s a good chance it’s built or run by <a href="https://www.scenichudson.org/">Scenic Hudson</a>. Their 45 parks throughout the region include local treasures such as Long Dock Park in Beacon, Poets’ Walk in Red Hook, and West Point Foundry in Cold Spring.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/ned-sullivan-of-scenic-hudson-2.jpg" alt="Ned Sullivan of Scenic Hudson" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>A handful of the many Scenic Hudson parks. Clockwise: Esplanade Park, Burger Hill (Photo: Zach Johnson), Mount Beacon Park, Mawignack Preserve (Photo: Robert Rodriguez, Jr.), Walkway Loop Trail (Photo: Pierce Johnston)Less visible to the public, though, is Scenic Hudson’s decades-long advocacy for the environmental health and beautification of the Hudson River. From its start in the 60s fighting — for 17 years! — against a project that would have destroyed part of the face of Storm King Mountain, Scenic Hudson has been at the forefront of the American environmental movement.</p>

<p>I recently spoke with Scenic Hudson president <a href="https://www.scenichudson.org/staff/ned-sullivan/">Ned Sullivan</a>, under whose stewardship the organization has thrived. I’ve had few conversations that have left me feeling so pumped up about the past, present, and future of our region — his view of the totality of the Hudson Valley’s history, and our place in it, is exhilarating.</p>

<h2 id="how-did-your-relationship-with-the-hudson-valley-begin">How did your relationship with the Hudson Valley begin?</h2>

<p>My family and I moved here from Maine, where I’d been the state environmental commissioner, about 20 years ago. We were originally from the Hudson Valley — I grew up in the Westchester, and my wife grew up in Woodstock.</p>

<h2 id="how-does-the-hudson-river-as-a-geological-feature-and-ecosystem-impact-the-hudson-valley-as-a-cultural-region">How does the Hudson River as a geological feature and ecosystem impact the Hudson Valley as a cultural region?</h2>

<p>The Hudson River and Hudson Valley are icons of America.</p>

<p>There’s so much American history that has played out here in the Hudson Valley, starting with the important role of the indigenous people who lived here in harmony with nature for centuries before the Europeans came, to the many battles of the American Revolution that were fought along the banks of the river, and beyond.</p>

<p>The Hudson River was considered a crucial strategic asset that the British were constantly trying to gain control of, and the colonial forces under General Washington were constantly fending them off. West Point was built during the Revolution to defend the Hudson Valley from the British.</p>

<p>In the 19th century there was the Hudson Valley School of painters, who captured the incredible beauty, the light, and the spiritual dimensions of the river. The Hudson Valley is often called the landscape that defined America. The Hudson River School painters captured the beauty of the region and shared it all over the world, and that was many people’s first view of America. That cultural tradition continues to this day, with so many photographers and painters and poets who are inspired by the region’s beauty.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/ned-sullivan-of-scenic-hudson-3.jpg" alt="Ned Sullivan of Scenic Hudson" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"><em><a href="https://www.metmuseum.org/art/collection/search/11310">Hudson River Scene</a></em>, John Frederick Kensett (1857)</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>During the Great Depression and World War II, Franklin D. Roosevelt led the nation and provided global leadership from his home in Hyde Park. Many of his experiments with social programs and economic recovery programs played out here in the Hudson Valley, such as the Civilian Conservation Corps that made improvements to parks, built cabins and walls and other features of the New York State parks system, and helped put people back to work.</p>

<p>The modern environmental movement launched right here in the Hudson Valley in the 60s. The founders of Scenic Hudson stood up to Con Edison, New York State, and the Federal Power Commission to oppose the blasting of the northern face off Storm King Mountain and the planting of a major pump storage facility there. It would’ve pumped hundreds of millions of gallons of Hudson River water out of the river each day to create power.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/ned-sullivan-of-scenic-hudson-4.jpg" alt="Ned Sullivan of Scenic Hudson" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>It took 17 years to defeat that project, but in the second year of the campaign they won a historic ruling that’s known in law books as the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scenic_Hudson_Preservation_Conference_v._Federal_Power_Commission">Scenic Hudson Decision</a>. It established the principle that citizens have standing to be heard in government decisions that affect the environment. Every time someone stands up in a public meeting to oppose a proposal that’s at odds with our view of the health or beauty of our community — or, if we stand up to support a project that will benefit our environs — that right traces its origins back to the Scenic Hudson decision and the Storm King case.</p>

<p>The Scenic Hudson decision became the foundation of the National Environmental Policy Act, this country’s seminal environmental law, which created the <a href="https://www.epa.gov/">Environmental Protection Agency</a> and a whole body of laws that protect the environment and give citizens a voice in shaping the environment around them.</p>

<p>The activism that led to that important victory continues today. All these traditions have carried forward into the present — the love of art, the agriculture that’s a crucial component of the Hudson Valley’s economy, the whole food movement, farm-to-table cooking. There’s a richness to our agricultural heritage, the beauty of the landscape that comes from farms, and now a movement to ensure that our agricultural practices are sustaining our environment and can be a solution to climate change rather than a source of greenhouse gasses.</p>

<p>All of these things work together to make the Hudson Valley a very important cultural landscape, but also a beautiful place to live, work, and raise a family.</p>

<h2 id="do-you-have-a-favorite-scenic-hudson-park">Do you have a favorite Scenic Hudson park?</h2>

<p>I think <a href="https://www.scenichudson.org/explore-the-valley/scenic-hudson-parks/poets-walk-park/">Poets’ Walk</a> in Red Hook is closest to my heart.</p>

<p>It happens to be in my town, and when I was first moving down from Maine and was trying to decide if I should join Scenic Hudson, I went to Poets’ Walk. I looked at that romantic landscape, the views of the river, and said to myself: “If Scenic Hudson  can create such a beautiful place for people to enjoy and connect with the inspiring power of the river, I want to work at that organization.”</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/ned-sullivan-of-scenic-hudson-5.jpg" alt="Ned Sullivan of Scenic Hudson" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center">Poets’ Walk in Red Hook</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Five years ago, when my wife Tara and I celebrated our 20th anniversary, I had a local artist make a painting of the view from Poets’ Walk, which includes the Kingston-Rhinecliff Bridge and Overlook Mountain above Woodstock. As I mentioned, she grew up in Woodstock, and she’s also in charge of all the New York State bridges in the Mid-Hudson Valley (from the Bear Mountain Bridge all the way up to the Rip Van Winkle), so Poets’ Walk captures the landscape of our life together.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.google.com/maps/search/?api=1&amp;query=41.9818055,-73.917674">Poets’ Walk Park</a></p>

<h2 id="its-probably-hard-to-pick-a-favorite-there-are-so-many">It’s probably hard to pick a favorite, there are so many.</h2>

<p>Right. I also love the views from <a href="https://www.scenichudson.org/explore-the-valley/scenic-hudson-parks/mount-beacon-park/">Mount Beacon</a>. I love being atop the fire tower and looking down at Storm King and the Hudson River and the New York City skyline.</p>

<p>I also love <a href="https://www.scenichudson.org/explore-the-valley/scenic-hudson-parks/falling-waters-preserve/">Falling Waters</a> in Saugerties, which is spectacular.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/ned-sullivan-of-scenic-hudson-6.jpg" alt="Ned Sullivan of Scenic Hudson" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center">Photo by <a href="https://www.devinpickering.net/">Devin Pickering</a></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="what-does-a-typical-day-look-like-for-you">What does a typical day look like for you?</h2>

<p>Every day I get up, have a healthy breakfast, and take my two border collies for a long walk.</p>

<p>Many days I’ll visit our parks to make sure they’re in good shape, particularly these days when we’re in lockdown and have to make sure that people enjoying our parks are keeping their social distance. That’s not part of my job specifically, but I just like to monitor how things are going. We have a terrific staff who are taking care of the parks through the COVID lockdown.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/ned-sullivan-of-scenic-hudson-7.jpg" alt="Ned Sullivan of Scenic Hudson" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center">West Point Foundry Reserve in Cold Spring. Photo by Robert Rodriguez, Jr.</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>I interact with the management team and with the entire organization. In addition to our staff doing a fabulous job of maintaining the parks, we’re continuing our campaigns throughout the Hudson Valley to protect our clean water, to stop the latest power plant that’s been proposed, and to advance legislation in Albany and in Washington.</p>

<p>I stay in touch with team leaders and frontline members of the organization who are doing such great work. I also interact with state legislators, our congressional delegation, county executives, and the Scenic Hudson board of directors.</p>

<p>Toward the end of the day, I typically go for a bike ride. I live close to a set of hills, and I bicycle uphill about 1200 feet and then coast back down before helping my family prepare for dinner together.</p>

<h2 id="what-else-do-you-enjoy-doing">What else do you enjoy doing?</h2>

<p>I love to kayak, and many weekends I get out on the river. I thoroughly enjoy connecting with the Hudson right on the surface of the water.</p>

<p>During wintertime, I love cross-country skiing. That’s my absolute passion.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/ned-sullivan-of-scenic-hudson-8.jpg" alt="Ned Sullivan of Scenic Hudson" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center">Photo by <a href="https://www.devinpickering.net/">Devin Pickering</a></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="is-there-anything-you-wish-hudson-valley-residents-knew-about-the-river">Is there anything you wish Hudson Valley residents knew about the river?</h2>

<p>People are pretty in-touch with the ecology of the river and beauty of nature, but they might not realize that the Hudson Valley is one of the most biologically diverse areas of New York State.</p>

<p>It’s an estuary, and the tidal effect of the river extends all the way up to the Troy Dam near Albany — there’s three feet of tide, and the mixing of fresh and salt water typically extends all the way to Bear Mountain and West Point, and some years and seasons it extends even farther.</p>

<p>That mixing of salt water and fresh water creates remarkable biological diversity, it makes for the wonderful wetlands we have here, and it facilitates the habitats for endangered and threatened animal and plant species we have here.</p>

<h2 id="do-you-have-a-go-to-coffee-or-beer-order-and-from-where">Do you have a go-to coffee or beer order, and from where?</h2>

<p>I love dark beers, and so <a href="https://www.keeganales.com/">Keegan Ales</a> over in Kingston is terrific.</p>

<p><a href="https://obercreekbrewing.com/">Obercreek Brewing</a> is down in Hughsonville in Southern Dutchess County, and is run by a member of our board, Alex Reese, whose mother Franny Reese was one of Scenic Hudson’s founders.</p>

<p>I also wanted to mention that my daughter, Annie Sullivan, is now the owner of a juice bar in the town of Red Hook. It’s called <a href="http://nourishjbonlineorder.com">Nourish</a>, and they make fresh, healthy, cold-pressed juices. It’s on East Market Street in Red Hook. You can see their website here: <a href="https://www.nourishjuiceredhook.com/">https://www.nourishjuiceredhook.com/</a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.google.com/maps/search/?api=1&amp;query=41.994872,-73.875251">Nourish Juice Bar</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Community" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’ve been to a park in the Hudson Valley, there’s a good chance it’s built or run by Scenic Hudson. Their 45 parks throughout the region include local treasures such as Long Dock Park in Beacon, Poets’ Walk in Red Hook, and West Point Foundry in Cold Spring.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jalani Lion</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jalani-lion/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jalani Lion" /><published>2020-07-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-07-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jalani-lion</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jalani-lion/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="hello-who-are-you-tell-us-about-yourself-what-are-you-passionate-about-what-do-you-enjoy-doing">Hello! Who are you? Tell us about yourself. What are you passionate about? What do you enjoy doing?</h2>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/jalani-lion-1.jpg" alt="Jalani Lion" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>I’m Jalani Lion, a recording and visual artist from Kingston, NY.</p>

<p>In 2015, I painted <em>In Memory of Adam (Jeff) McQueen, Kaireem Meeks, Jr., Dante Crump, Jonte Clark &amp; Jeffrey D’Aguilar</em>, the mural on Franklin Street in Kingston. McQueen, Meeks, Crump, and Clark, all Kingston residents, lost their lives in a Village of Saugerties car crash. D’Aguilar, also of Kingston, lost his life after losing control of his car in Pine Plains. This mural serves as sacred grounds to the people of Kingston. Their lives are celebrated, mourned, and have brought family and friends closer together at this mural. This was the start to the murals I’ve painted.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/jalani-lion-2.jpg" alt="Jalani Lion" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center">Jalani in front of his first mural, on Franklin Street in Kingston.</figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="what-inspires-your-murals-and-your-music">What inspires your murals and your music?</h2>

<p>Emotions inspire my music and art. Whether it be love or heartache, happiness or depression, positivity or persevering through life’s struggles; emotion is always the inspiration behind my work.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/jalani-lion-3.jpg" alt="Jalani Lion" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="how-did-the-black-lives-matter-mural-come-about">How did the Black Lives Matter mural come about?</h2>

<p><a href="https://opositivefestival.org/kingston/">O+</a> is a non-profit organization located in the Hudson Valley that empowers communities to take control of their collective wellbeing through exchange of art, music and wellness.</p>

<p>Recently, O+ reached out to me about a week after the murder of George Floyd and wanted to embark on creating a mural representing anti-racism and ending police brutality. O+ already had the resources and a building to paint in mind. They supplied paint, ladders, support, and gave me complete creative freedom with this mural. The only rule was that they preferred for it not to be political. Within a week the new mural was complete. It was a collaborative effort between myself and two other artists. I handled the portraits, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/dinakravtsov/">Dina Kravstov</a> handled the flowers, and Mat Schulze handled the lettering. The chemistry flowed naturally and it was an enjoyable experience.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/jalani-lion-4.jpg" alt="Jalani Lion" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>The Black Lives Matter mural on Broadway in Kingston depicts three unarmed African Americans who were killed at the hands of police — the victims’ names are Breonna Taylor and George Floyd — and by white vigilantes — the victim’s name is Ahmaud Arbery.</p>

<p>As tragic and heartbreaking as each of these recent deaths are, it can be said that the loss of these people caused a modern day revolution in America, and even the world. With protests, riots ,and support from all over the globe, American police are now being held accountable for their actions, racists are being exposed, and justice is being served. It is my hope that this mural can provoke thought and emotion on this country’s recent events. I hope it can serve as a symbol for positive change in the country, as well as the city of Kingston.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/jalani-lion-5.jpg" alt="Jalani Lion" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Most Kingston/Hudson Valley natives were supportive; however, there were a few civilians frustrated by the mural and stated “All Lives Matter.” After <a href="https://www.dailyfreeman.com/news/local-news/midtown-kingston-mural-sends-black-lives-matter-message/article_0736992a-b314-11ea-986e-7735d4d785dc.html#1">the</a> <em><a href="https://www.dailyfreeman.com/news/local-news/midtown-kingston-mural-sends-black-lives-matter-message/article_0736992a-b314-11ea-986e-7735d4d785dc.html#1">Daily Freeman</a></em><a href="https://www.dailyfreeman.com/news/local-news/midtown-kingston-mural-sends-black-lives-matter-message/article_0736992a-b314-11ea-986e-7735d4d785dc.html#1">‘s article on the Black Lives Matter mural</a> was released to the public, tensions rose. A lot of hate-driven and contradictory comments were made on the <em>Daily Freeman</em>‘s Facebook post, such as “white lives matter” or “that’s racist,” and much more. Along with this, there were counter comments enraged by the hateful comments, almost like social media protesters. Amidst these two opposing forces, there were people who commented how much they loved, adored, and appreciated the mural.</p>

<p>Although conflict was never the goal of this mural, awareness was; similar to the protests taking place all around the world. Change is not always easy and will not be taken lightly by all, but it is necessary for this country to move forward in a positive direction.</p>

<p>Looking ahead, I can’t imagine what the future holds. Less than a month ago, this was just another building on Broadway in Kingston, NY. Today, it is making news articles, touching people’s hearts, and grabbing attention and support from diverse people all over the state and country. I hold myself to high standards. Once I reach a goal, there’s always another goal waiting. I’m grateful and humbled by all the positive feedback. With all the love and support that I have received lately, I’m confident that many good things will come out of it.</p>

<h2 id="walk-us-through-a-typical-day">Walk us through a typical day.</h2>

<p>I work Monday through Friday at Young Lions Daycare, owned by mother, Jeanette Washington. When I’m not working at the daycare, I’m working on artwork for clientele or creating music.</p>

<h2 id="how-has-the-hudson-valley-influenced-or-impacted-your-creative-work">How has the Hudson Valley influenced or impacted your creative work?</h2>

<p>Opportunities given by the Hudson Valley have caused me to create pieces I may not have created had the opportunity not arose. Great feedback from said pieces have pushed me to work harder.</p>

<h2 id="what-do-you-hope-to-see-for-the-hudson-valley-in-the-next-five-years">What do you hope to see for the Hudson Valley in the next five years?</h2>

<p>Positive change in all areas. A positive future. Equality. Fair treatment. A great support system for the youth to enhance their future.</p>

<h2 id="where-can-we-see-more-of-your-work">Where can we see more of your work?</h2>

<p>The best place to see all my work, big and small, is my Instagram page: <a href="https://www.instagram.com/iamyounglion2/">@iamyounglion2</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Music" /><category term="Visual Arts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! Who are you? Tell us about yourself. What are you passionate about? What do you enjoy doing?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jon Bowermaster</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jon-bowermaster/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jon Bowermaster" /><published>2020-06-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-06-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jon-bowermaster</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jon-bowermaster/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="hello-who-are-you-tell-us-about-yourself-what-are-you-passionate-about-what-do-you-enjoy-doing">Hello! Who are you? Tell us about yourself. What are you passionate about? What do you enjoy doing?</h2>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/jon-bowermaster-1.jpg" alt="Jon Bowermaster" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>I am a writer, filmmaker, and adventurer — eleven books, hundreds of magazine and web stories, more than thirty documentary films — who appreciates the wide variety of subjects I’ve had the luxury to discover and learn about, all driven by a singular concern for the health of our environment and the beauty of the remote corners of the planet. Passion? No matter the media, storytelling.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/jon-bowermaster-2.jpg" alt="Jon Bowermaster" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="how-did-you-discover-the-hudson-valley">How did you discover the Hudson Valley?</h2>

<p>Like so many creative persons who end up here, I came because I much preferred waking up surrounded by green than by the cement of the big city. I started visiting Woodstock from Brooklyn in the mid-1980s and in 1988 officially made my escape to Stone Ridge. Though I’ve traveled quite a lot since then (90 countries or so), lived off and on in France for ten years and have made films on every continent… I always kept my home here, always ready and happy to return.</p>

<h2 id="walk-us-through-a-typical-day">Walk us through a typical day.</h2>

<p>No such thing. Though I do seem to spend a fair amount of time these days chained to a desk chair… too much time, actually.</p>

<p>For the past ten years I’ve mostly been making documentary films, of varied subjects: Two films about the environmental messes of Louisiana; two in Antarctica, including the first 3D film shot there; three films in my anti-fracking “Dear” series (<em>Dear Governor Cuomo</em>, <em>Dear Governor Brown</em>, and <em>Dear President Obama</em>); <em>Ghost Fleet</em>, about the tragic truth that many commercial fisherman, especially in Southeast Asia, are slaves.</p>

<p>For the past five years my team and I have produced a series of short films about the Hudson Valley (<a href="http://www.hudsonriverstories.com">www.hudsonriverstories.com</a>), which has happily kept me closer to home.</p>

<p>Each film is different: Different storytelling techniques, different funding, different filming teams, different distribution, different locations. All of which is a way of going back to that query about “ordinary days.”</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/jon-bowermaster-3.jpg" alt="Jon Bowermaster" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center">No typical days.</figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="do-you-have-a-go-to-coffee-or-beer-order-and-from-where">Do you have a go-to coffee or beer order, and from where?</h2>

<p>I’m a big fan of the tasting room at the <a href="http://www.suarezfamilybrewery.com/">Suarez Family Brewery</a> outside Hudson.</p>

<h2 id="where-do-you-do-your-best-creative-work">Where do you do your best creative work?</h2>

<p>When I was writing more, and traveling more, I always enjoyed the physical act of writing. Making notes. With paper and pen. No matter what kind of day it had been — for ten years I led a series of National Geographic-funded expeditions by sea kayak that took me and my teams around the world, so many of those end-of-days were on river banks or ocean coastlines — I liked looking for some shade, a place under a tree to record the day.</p>

<p>I hesitate to call what I was doing under those various trees “writing”;  more like note-taking, or in modern nomenclature, journaling. The truth is I don’t really enjoy the process of writing, whether a story or book. For me, that is hard, painstaking work. I love having written. Whenever I hear someone say they “love to write,” I question them.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/jon-bowermaster-4.jpg" alt="Jon Bowermaster" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="how-has-the-hudson-valley-influenced-or-impacted-your-creative-work">How has the Hudson Valley influenced or impacted your creative work?</h2>

<p>I went to a small private university in the dead-center of the country. But for some reason that I can’t recall or explain on my dormitory wall I had a poster of a painting of the Hudson River by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Bierstadt">Albert Bierstadt</a>, one of the original of the Hudson River School. I’d never visited the Hudson Valley, not sure what attracted me to that poster, but like so many creative people, going back a couple centuries, the Hudson Valley has lured an incredible array of musicians, artists, writers and, now, environmentalists.</p>

<p>I am out in public often, sharing our short films about the Hudson River Valley and I am convinced, though have no empirical data, that there are more environmentalists per capita living here than anywhere in the country. That is in part because the Valley is legitimately known as the birthplace of American environmentalism, going back to the 1960s and a series of laws that sparked groups to form, activists to congregate, voices to be raised. Sometimes I think we take for granted the level of environmental activism that surrounds us; few regions have the abundance of groups, big and small, working on these issues, day in, day out, on our behalf.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/jon-bowermaster-5.jpg" alt="Jon Bowermaster" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center">Talking about climate change and Antarctica at the United Nations.</figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="whats-surprised-you-most-about-living-and-working-in-the-hudson-valley">What’s surprised you most about living and working in the Hudson Valley?</h2>

<p>After three decades it seems I find a new road every day.</p>

<h2 id="whats-been-challenging-about-doing-your-work-here">What’s been challenging about doing your work here?</h2>

<p>When I was traveling a lot, the fact that the airports were so far away. I joked that if I’d known I was going to travel that much I would have bought a condo across from Newark International.</p>

<h2 id="what-do-you-hope-to-see-for-the-hudson-valley-in-the-next-five-years">What do you hope to see for the Hudson Valley in the next five years?</h2>

<p>A continued move to renewable energy and energy efficiency. While New York has lead the way nationally in keeping fossil fuel development like fracking out of the state, the Hudson Valley is still home to pipelines, railways, and barges carrying crude oil, each of which comes with the risk of serious accident. There are also proposed new gas plants hoping to be built along the Hudson River, which would be taking any clean energy plans promoted by governors, legislators, or environmental groups  backwards rather than forwards.</p>

<h2 id="are-you-part-of-any-local-groups-or-communities-youd-like-to-mention">Are you part of any local groups or communities you’d like to mention?</h2>

<p>We are lucky to have some 300 groups working on environmental issues from Albany to NYC. Follow your local groups but also the bigger ones too (<a href="https://www.scenichudson.org/">Scenic Hudson</a>, <a href="https://www.riverkeeper.org/">Riverkeeper</a>, <a href="https://www.clearwater.org/">Clearwater</a>, the <a href="https://www.nrdc.org/">Natural Resources Defense Council</a>); there is an <em>incredible</em> amount of information out there about what’s really going on in our backyard, if you just pay attention.</p>

<h2 id="anything-you-want-to-plug-or-promote">Anything you want to plug or promote?</h2>

<p>Everyone who cares about the Hudson Valley should watch our series of short films, <em><a href="https://www.hudsonriverstories.com/hudson-river-at-risk/">The Hudson, A River at Risk</a></em> and <em><a href="https://www.hudsonriverstories.com/hope-on-the-hudson/">Hope on the Hudson</a></em>. One will make you angry, the other make you smile. They work well together.</p>

<p>I also do a weekly radio show on Radio Kingston, the <a href="https://radiokingston.org/en/archive/filter/green-radio-hour-w-jon-bowermaster">Green Radio Hour with Jon Bowermaster</a>, live at 3pm on Sundays, or archived at <a href="https://radiokingston.org/en/archive/filter/green-radio-hour-w-jon-bowermaster">radiokingston.org</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Film" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! Who are you? Tell us about yourself. What are you passionate about? What do you enjoy doing?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">NeeNee Rushie of The Big Takeover</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/neenee-rushie-of-the-big-takeover/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NeeNee Rushie of The Big Takeover" /><published>2020-06-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-06-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/neenee-rushie-of-the-big-takeover</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/neenee-rushie-of-the-big-takeover/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="hello-who-are-you-tell-us-about-yourself-what-are-you-passionate-about-what-do-you-enjoy-doing">Hello! Who are you? Tell us about yourself. What are you passionate about? What do you enjoy doing?</h2>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/neenee-rushie-of-the-big-takeover-1.jpg" alt="NeeNee Rushie of The Big Takeover" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Hi! My name is NeeNee Rushie. I front <a href="https://www.bigtakeoverband.com/">The Big Takeover</a>. The Big Takeover has been creating reggae-like, soul-type music for the past 12 years. We have released four full length albums, and will soon release a fifth. We have toured nationally and have been recognized as the Hudson Valley’s Best Band in 2018.</p>

<p>I am very passionate about the project overall — from writing, to recording, to touring, and everything in between. My favorite part is performing live. I love the feeling I get when I am allowed to channel all my passion into a microphone and hear and feel the passion of my bandmates.</p>

<h2 id="how-did-you-discover-the-hudson-valley">How did you discover the Hudson Valley?</h2>

<p>I went to college in New Paltz. I discovered New Paltz by chance, really. When I visited for the first time, something about the mountains in the background and the narrow main street that takes you through the bustling town, reminded me of the town I grew up in — Port Antonio, Jamaica.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/neenee-rushie-of-the-big-takeover-2.jpg" alt="NeeNee Rushie of The Big Takeover" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center">NeeNee and The Big Takeover at <a href="https://mountainjam.com/">Mountain Jam</a>. Photo © Matthew Conde</figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="walk-us-through-a-typical-day">Walk us through a typical day.</h2>

<p>In addition to fronting The Big Takeover, I am also a public school teacher. I work in Poughkeepsie city. My typical day would include me balancing my two careers. I teach during the weekdays, and dedicate my weekends to touring with The Big Takeover. We usually tour regionally during the school year, and nationally during the summer months.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/neenee-rushie-of-the-big-takeover-3.jpg" alt="NeeNee Rushie of The Big Takeover" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center">NeeNee and The Big Takeover. Photo © <a href="https://www.ariusphoto.com/">Arius Photography</a></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="where-do-you-do-your-best-creative-work">Where do you do your best creative work?</h2>

<p>I feed very heavily off of my band mates. I rarely write independently, so I do my best creative work when I’m with <a href="https://www.instagram.com/robkissner/">Rob Kissner</a> (the bassist, and primary music writer), or with more members of the band.</p>

<h2 id="how-has-the-hudson-valley-influenced-or-impacted-your-creative-work">How has the Hudson Valley influenced or impacted your creative work?</h2>

<p>The Hudson Valley is filled with quite unique, creative, and open-minded individuals. This has forced us a musical group to maintain a high standard with the music we publish and the stage shows we perform. We know that in the Hudson Valley, the audience that comes to see us play will have a sophisticated ear that is very familiar with a certain quality of music. So we try to impress with our recordings and performances. Our Hudson Valley musical colleagues publish and perform high-quality music as well, so they provide a proper bar for us to meet consistently. Being Hudson Valley-based has helped us to continue to refine our craft.</p>

<h2 id="anything-you-want-to-plug-or-promote">Anything you want to plug or promote?</h2>

<table>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>The Big Takeover has recently released a single called <em>Weight of the World</em> [<a href="https://open.spotify.com/album/7i2QvVWgwSOxTVwj9HTFSS?highlight=spotify:track:42HANbwn7y0gxuNTu5fSml">Spotify</a></td>
      <td><a href="https://music.apple.com/us/album/weight-of-the-world-single/1511256949">Apple Music</a>]. It is a song that we recorded remotely in response to the current quarantine and COVID situation. It is available on all streaming platforms. We also created a video remotely for this single.</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Music" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello! Who are you? Tell us about yourself. What are you passionate about? What do you enjoy doing?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jimmy DeCicco of Super Coffee</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jimmy-decicco/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jimmy DeCicco of Super Coffee" /><published>2020-05-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-05-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jimmy-decicco</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jimmy-decicco/"><![CDATA[<p><em>This post was sponsored by local startup accelerator Accel7.</em></p>

<p>Jimmy DeCicco and his brothers Jake and Jordan grew up in Kingston, attended Kingston High School, and excelled at both <a href="https://www.recordonline.com/article/20130728/sports/307270340">sports and academics</a>. Now, they’re working together as the founders of Super Coffee, a bottled coffee-based energy drink that competed on Shark Tank and has gone on to be stocked in supermarkets and gyms around the country.</p>

<p>The premise is simple — typical energy drinks aren’t healthy, but plenty of people still need a boost beyond what a mere cup of coffee can provide. Originally designed for the needs of student athletes and other early-to-wake people, Super Coffee is a mixture of iced coffee and keto-friendly protein, oil, and fruit extract that prevents the usual caffeine crash.</p>

<p>The company is now worth $200 million.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/jimmy-decicco-2.jpg" alt="Jimmy DeCicco of Super Coffee" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center">The DeCicco brothers, who were listed on last year’s <a href="https://www.forbes.com/pictures/5be1a75da7ea43705916322a/kitu-life-jordan-decicco/#6e2e16874e3d">Forbes 30 Under 30</a>.</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>I spoke to Jimmy DeCicco, the eldest brother and CEO of the company, about growing up in the Hudson Valley and what life looks like now.</p>

<h2 id="hello-who-are-you-tell-us-about-yourself-what-are-you-passionate-about-what-do-you-enjoy-doing">Hello! Who are you? Tell us about yourself. What are you passionate about? What do you enjoy doing?</h2>

<p>My name is Jimmy DeCicco and I am the Oldest Brother and CEO at <a href="https://shop.drinksupercoffee.com/">Super Coffee</a>.</p>

<p>I played football at Kingston High School (‘11) and then at Colgate University (‘15) and sports have always been a major part of my identity. I am competitive and compassionate with a deep desire to win with teammates who share a similar determination and passion for a common goal.</p>

<p>My two younger brothers, Jake and Jordan, and I started Super Coffee in 2015 as tired student-athletes and we’ve been building ever since!</p>

<p>When I’m not working on the business I’m a fitness enthusiast, an avid bow-hunter, and a snowboarder when there’s snow.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/jimmy-decicco-3.jpg" alt="Jimmy DeCicco of Super Coffee" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center">The DeCicco Brothers with NFL Legend Reggie Bush at the 2020 Roc Nation Brunch, sponsored by Super Coffee, ahead of the Grammys. (Photo by Erik Voake/Getty Images for Roc Nation)</figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="how-did-you-discover-the-hudson-valley">How did you discover the Hudson Valley?</h2>

<p>My dad was born and raised in Kingston and he raised us in Hurley, NY. I attended Kingston High School class of 2011.</p>

<h2 id="walk-us-through-a-typical-day">Walk us through a typical day.</h2>

<p>I wake up early, usually between 5 and 6am. I try to get some level activity or fitness done in the morning — if I don’t make it to the gym I’ll usually just jump rope, stretch, and hit some pull-ups and push-ups at my apartment. Movement in the morning is key for me. I usually practice intermittent fasting, so I only drink water and black coffee in the morning with no food til lunch time. I then catch up on my email from 6 to 7am and I’m usually at the office by 7:30am.</p>

<p>My day is typically filled with team calls or meetings — I oversee marketing and finance. I’m in charge of investor relations so oftentimes I’m pitching investors or managing expectations of existing investors. I try to leave the office by 6 or 7pm. If I didn’t workout in the morning I’ll workout after work, eat a meal, try to read 5-10 pages of a book and then I’m asleep by 9:30 or 10pm.</p>

<h2 id="do-you-have-a-go-to-coffee-or-beer-order-and-from-where">Do you have a go-to coffee or beer order, and from where?</h2>

<p>When I’m not drinking too much Super Coffee my go-to coffee order is a red-eye (coffee with a shot of espresso) from <a href="https://www.roughdraftny.com/">Rough Draft</a>.</p>

<h2 id="where-do-you-do-your-best-creative-work">Where do you do your best creative work?</h2>

<p>I do my best creative work from places outside of my apartment and office. Since I spend most of my time at the office or at my apartment, I use that time to hammer through projects and day-to-day responsibilities. When I want to be creative I usually wander into a coffee shop, cafe, or coworking space. The new environment helps me come up with new ideas.</p>

<h2 id="how-has-the-hudson-valley-influenced-or-impacted-your-creative-work">How has the Hudson Valley influenced or impacted your creative work?</h2>

<p>The Hudson Valley is really my personal motivation and inspiration. To me, the Hudson Valley represents freedom and opportunity. I’ve been living in NYC for the last 4 years and though it’s productive for building our business, it feels confining and suppressing. I try to escape to the Hudson Valley to explore hikes in the Catskills or go to Sunday dinner at my grandmother’s house in East Kingston. A weekend upstate is like pressing the reset button which leads to more productive, creative output.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/jimmy-decicco-4.jpg" alt="Jimmy DeCicco of Super Coffee" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center">Jimmy, Jake, and Jordan celebrate new product launch of Super Creamer in October 2018.</figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="whats-surprised-you-most-about-living-and-working-in-the-hudson-valley">What’s surprised you most about living and working in the Hudson Valley?</h2>

<p>Growing up in the Hudson Valley, I took its beauty and opportunity for granted. Now that I live in NYC, I crave getting back into the Hudson Valley as much as possible. We’ve been very fortunate that our work has taken us all over the country to every major city and state. After seeing it all, I have an even greater desire to build my life in the Hudson Valley. It truly is one of the most beautiful and unique areas in the country.</p>

<h2 id="whats-been-challenging-about-doing-your-work-here">What’s been challenging about doing your work here?</h2>

<p>Working from the Hudson Valley has some accessibility issues. It’s difficult to host meetings with prospective clients and investors and it’s difficult to attract talented employees away from their lives in big cities.</p>

<h2 id="what-do-you-hope-to-see-for-the-hudson-valley-in-the-next-five-years">What do you hope to see for the Hudson Valley in the next five years?</h2>

<p>Continued development and innovation. The Hudson Valley is ripe for innovation and industry. I’d like to see the Hudson Valley attract entrepreneurs and innovators who solve problems and create opportunities for their local and national communities.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/jimmy-decicco-5.jpg" alt="Jimmy DeCicco of Super Coffee" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center">Jordan (KHS ‘13), Jake (KHS ‘12), and Jimmy (KHS ‘11) give the commencement speech at the 2018 Kingston High School graduation at Dietz Stadium</figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="are-you-part-of-any-local-groups-or-communities-youd-like-to-mention">Are you part of any local groups or communities you’d like to mention?</h2>

<p>Growing up in Hurley, our mom worked at the YMCA in Kingston; we were pretty much raised there so it will always be a part of our identity and it’s an obligatory stop on each visit to Kingston. I try to stay involved in <a href="https://www.facebook.com/KingstonTigersFootball/">Kingston Tigers Football</a> whether it be helping out at practice working out with the student-athletes when I’m home.</p>

<h2 id="anything-you-want-to-plug-or-promote">Anything you want to plug or promote?</h2>

<p>Kingston High School, especially KHS athletics, needs support from its alumni. Please don’t hesitate to reach out, get involved, and give back.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Business" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This post was sponsored by local startup accelerator Accel7.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bryan Meador</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/bryan-meador/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bryan Meador" /><published>2020-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/bryan-meador</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/bryan-meador/"><![CDATA[<p><em>This post was sponsored by local startup accelerator Accel7.</em></p>

<h2 id="hello-who-are-you-tell-us-about-yourself-what-are-you-passionate-about-what-do-you-enjoy-doing">Hello! Who are you? Tell us about yourself. What are you passionate about? What do you enjoy doing?</h2>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/bryan-meador-1.jpg" alt="Bryan Meador" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Hi! I’m Bryan. I’m an artist, designer and Founder of <a href="https://www.plantseads.com/">Plant Seads</a>, a design firm based in Kingston, NY. I’m passionate about the environment, design, and giving people ways to make their lives a little more green right now. I see enormous potential in designing products that take advantage of existing infrastructure by augmenting it in a way that weaves together ecology and urban living. That’s the core of what we’re doing, and it’s reflected in our name: “Seads” is an acronym that stands for Sustainable Ecology, Adaptive Design.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/bryan-meador-2.jpg" alt="Bryan Meador" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center">📸 by <a href="https://www.justinbettman.com/">Justin Bettman</a></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Despite the daily avalanche of bad news, I’m optimistic about the future. I’m a firm believer that we have to create the future we want — so rather than wait for a wave of city-scale eco-friendly environmental design to happen, I’m designing products from sustainable materials that enable people to start transforming our built environment right now.</p>

<p>The first of these projects is a planter that I’ve designed to fit into chain link fencing, transforming fences into vertical gardens. These planters, which I call SeadPods, are manufactured right here in the Hudson Valley from recycled milk jugs and will be available later this year.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/bryan-meador-3.jpg" alt="Bryan Meador" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>By converting fences and other vertical spaces into gardens, we’re able to make progress on a few important environmental fronts all at once. Vertical gardens absorb excess rainwater, keeping our waterways healthier and less congested during storms. They clean the air of particulate matter and CO2 while releasing oxygen, and they absorb excess sound, making our cities more livable. All while cleaning our environment of single use plastic that would otherwise pollute our communities.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/bryan-meador-4.jpg" alt="Bryan Meador" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="how-did-you-discover-the-hudson-valley">How did you discover the Hudson Valley?</h2>

<p>I’m originally from Oklahoma and came to New York when I enrolled at <a href="https://www.newschool.edu/parsons/">Parsons School of Design</a> in NYC. I lived and worked in the city for almost 10 years, but found myself yearning for a more natural environment, so I began spending weekends in the Hudson Valley. After a while, I couldn’t bear the idea of leaving to head back to the city on Sunday nights, so I moved upstate and haven’t looked back since.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/bryan-meador-5.jpg" alt="Bryan Meador" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="walk-us-through-a-typical-day">Walk us through a typical day.</h2>

<p>I wake up fairly early each day and start things off with a solo walk along the Hudson River. This ritual keeps me grounded in the natural world and is constantly inspiring new ideas and solutions. Watching Mother Nature grow and adapt from one season to another, watching the tide come in and out, seeing the birds soar above the water it puts me in a frame of mind that I really treasure and helps me throughout the day. I’ll generally get down to business by 9 and I’m working through the day until 5 or so, punctuated by meals and shorter walks to help me stay fresh.</p>

<h2 id="do-you-have-a-go-to-coffee-or-beer-order-and-from-where">Do you have a go-to coffee or beer order, and from where?</h2>

<p>A hot black coffee from <a href="https://www.roughdraftny.com/">Rough Draft</a> is like literal jet fuel for me. I love the stuff, and to sit down with a cup and get busy in their space is one of the things I look forward to most after this quarantine is over.</p>

<h2 id="where-do-you-do-your-best-creative-work">Where do you do your best creative work?</h2>

<p>While I love to work in coffee shops and cafés, I do my best work at home. When I’m in the zone I can really delve into a problem for hours until it’s really solved, and the solitude and quiet of home is perfect for that kind of deep dive.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/bryan-meador-6.jpg" alt="Bryan Meador" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="how-has-the-hudson-valley-influenced-or-impacted-your-creative-work">How has the Hudson Valley influenced or impacted your creative work?</h2>

<p>Being surrounded by nature is hugely inspiring, and fuels my creativity daily, so that’s a huge benefit of living and working in the Hudson Valley. It’s also amazing to be close to a major metropolitan area, but not within it. Having access to all the resources and communities of a large city but the comfort and open spaces of the country. We have several huge projects coming together for our launch this year in which we’ve been able to partner with some great urban renewal and urban agriculture based organizations in NYC. It’s easy to run in for a quick meeting or to deliver products when we’re just an hour or two away.</p>

<h2 id="whats-surprised-you-most-about-living-and-working-in-the-hudson-valley">What’s surprised you most about living and working in the Hudson Valley?</h2>

<p>The amount of resources available and the willingness of people to help has been mind-blowing. For example, we have worked extensively with the <a href="https://www.newpaltz.edu/hvamc/">Hudson Valley Additive Manufacturing Center at SUNY New Paltz</a> during our prototyping process. <a href="https://www.newpaltz.edu/ocm/admins/daniel-freedman/">Dan Freedman</a> and his team over there are incredibly knowledgeable and have some of the most advanced additive manufacturing equipment on the east coast. Having access to this technology enabled us to develop a product quickly by using rapid prototyping and an iterative design process that helps us learn fast and keep our process lean and agile.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/bryan-meador-7.jpg" alt="Bryan Meador" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="whats-been-challenging-about-doing-your-work-here">What’s been challenging about doing your work here?</h2>

<p>Winters can be long and bleak in the Hudson Valley, but they also offer a moment of pause and deep reflection that can be really helpful, especially for someone like me who likes to move fast.</p>

<h2 id="what-do-you-hope-to-see-for-the-hudson-valley-in-the-next-five-years">What do you hope to see for the Hudson Valley in the next five years?</h2>

<p>I’d love to see more eco-minded companies starting up in the area. There’s a built-in community here that’s hungry for this kind of design and I see enormous potential for big change to happen in this area. Future-oriented groups of young people getting together to make cool stuff happen have all the resources they need in the Hudson Valley, and its natural beauty cannot be beat.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/bryan-meador-8.jpg" alt="Bryan Meador" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="are-you-part-of-any-local-groups-or-communities-youd-like-to-mention">Are you part of any local groups or communities you’d like to mention?</h2>

<p>The <a href="https://www.kingstonymcafarmproject.org/">Kingston YMCA Farm Project</a> is doing amazing work. <a href="http://kingstonhappenings.org/doers-dreamers-kaycee-wimbish/">KayCee Wimbish</a> runs this project and is a real rockstar. She’s doing an incredible job of teaching kids about gardening and ecology right in the heart of Kingston. It’s urban/agricultural projects like this that I think will bring us towards a brighter future and I’m excited to do an installation of SeadPods with them later this year.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/bryan-meador-9.jpg" alt="Bryan Meador" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="anything-you-want-to-plug-or-promote">Anything you want to plug or promote?</h2>

<p><a href="https://plantseads.com">Plant Seads</a>!</p>

<hr />

<p><em>Pictures courtesy of Plant Seads. Outdoor photos taken at the Kingston YMCA Farm Project. Portraits by Justin Bettman.</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Business" /><category term="Design" /><category term="Visual Arts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This post was sponsored by local startup accelerator Accel7.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rikki Snyder</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/rikki-snyder/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rikki Snyder" /><published>2020-04-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/rikki-snyder</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/rikki-snyder/"><![CDATA[<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/rikki-snyder-1.jpg" alt="Rikki Snyder" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Beacon-based Rikki Snyder is a well-known food, lifestyle, and interior photographer whose work you may have seen in <em>Country Living</em>, <em>Westchester Home</em>, and <em>The New York Times Cooking</em>; campaigns for Blue Apron, Cape Cod Potato Chips, and Bed, Bath, and Beyond; and books like <em>The Simple Lunchbox</em>, <em>Crafting a Colorful Home</em>, and <em>31 Days of Local Food</em>. She also photographed the second annual Kingston Design Showhouse, featured in the Creative Hudson Valley <a href="https://creativehudsonvalley.com/maryline-damour/">interview with Maryline Damour</a>.</p>

<h2 id="hello-who-are-you-tell-us-about-yourself-what-are-you-passionate-about-what-do-you-enjoy-doing">Hello! Who are you? Tell us about yourself. What are you passionate about? What do you enjoy doing?</h2>

<p>Hi! I’m Rikki. I’m a photographer specializing in food, interiors and lifestyle. I’m super passionate about my work and after doing this for 10 years I still love it just as much as the day I started! When I’m not working, you can almost always find me in the kitchen experimenting with new recipes because I love to cook. I also love to read up on nutrition which is a new(er) found passion of mine.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/rikki-snyder-2.jpg" alt="Rikki Snyder" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="how-did-you-discover-the-hudson-valley">How did you discover the Hudson Valley?</h2>

<p>I am actually a Hudson Valley native! I grew up outside of Poughkeepsie. After going to photography school in MA and then moving to NYC for a while, I found myself back in the Hudson Valley… right in Beacon!</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/rikki-snyder-3.jpg" alt="Rikki Snyder" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="walk-us-through-a-typical-day">Walk us through a typical day.</h2>

<p>I have two kinds of typical days being a freelance photographer. I am either at home editing photos and working on emails/back end of the business or I am out and about on a shoot. I love the balance of the two because when I’m working from home I can stay in and make a nice breakfast, hang out with my pup and take things a little slower. When I’m on a shoot, especially if it’s in the city, I’m up super early and it’s all go-go-go! But I love having that balance.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/rikki-snyder-4.jpg" alt="Rikki Snyder" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="do-you-have-a-go-to-coffee-or-beer-order-and-from-where">Do you have a go-to coffee or beer order, and from where?</h2>

<p>My go-to coffee order at the moment is a turmeric latte with almond milk from Ella’s in Beacon! <em>[Ed. note: <a href="https://www.ellasbellasbeacon.com/">Ella’s Bellas</a> was recently sold and the location is now <a href="https://www.instagram.com/kitchen.coffee.beacon/">Kitchen &amp; Coffee</a>, but it’s kept most of the old menu, including the turmeric latte. I highly recommend it too!]</em> And my favorite cocktail is the Snuff Box at <a href="https://www.brasserie292.com/">Brasserie 292</a> in Poughkeepsie.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/rikki-snyder-5.jpg" alt="Rikki Snyder" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="where-do-you-do-your-best-creative-work">Where do you do your best creative work?</h2>

<p>Usually when I’m in a certain environment surrounded by something beautiful. That typically  means on a pretty farm or somewhere where color and nature is very present.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/rikki-snyder-6.jpg" alt="Rikki Snyder" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="how-has-the-hudson-valley-influenced-or-impacted-your-creative-work">How has the Hudson Valley influenced or impacted your creative work?</h2>

<p>I don’t think I knew how much the Hudson Valley impacted my creative work until I moved away! I realized just how beautiful the area is and that growing up here had such a significant impact on my work. I’d honestly say that if I didn’t grow up here my work wouldn’t exist! It has influenced me so immensely.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/rikki-snyder-7.jpg" alt="Rikki Snyder" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="whats-surprised-you-most-about-living-and-working-in-the-hudson-valley">What’s surprised you most about living and working in the Hudson Valley?</h2>

<p>How so many people have ties to the Hudson Valley in one way or another and how the community of creatives that now live here keeps growing which is super exciting.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/rikki-snyder-8.jpg" alt="Rikki Snyder" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="anything-you-want-to-plug-or-promote">Anything you want to plug or promote?</h2>

<p>I am always looking for homes to photograph and pitch to media outlets so if anyone has a home they think would be great I’d love to get in touch!</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/rikki-snyder-9.jpg" alt="Rikki Snyder" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Photography" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Easton LaChappelle</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/easton-lachappelle/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Easton LaChappelle" /><published>2020-03-31T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-03-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/easton-lachappelle</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/easton-lachappelle/"><![CDATA[<p>When he was just 14, Easton LaChappelle built his first working robotic arm out of fishing line, LEGO, and off-the-shelf electric tubing. The 10 years since then have been a whirlwind of activity, from showcasing his work to President Obama at the White House science fair, to getting seed funding from motivational speaker Tony Robbins, to starting his company Unlimited Tomorrow and moving it from Colorado to Rhinebeck.</p>

<p>It’s a cold day in early December when I drive to Unlimited Tomorrow’s headquarters, just past downtown Rhinebeck. The building looks unassuming, and from the outside I have trouble imagining it as the home base of a company about to change the world of medical prosthetics. That changes as soon as I step inside.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/easton-lachappelle-2.jpg" alt="Easton LaChappelle" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>The space feels very tech-company-meets-Hudson-Valley: concrete floors, wooden walls, lots of whiteboards and desks and people working on CAD software. In the corner past the entrance is a powered exoskeleton. Through a doorway, I can see an array of industrial-grade 3D printers. I’m starting to get an <em>Iron Man</em> vibe.</p>

<p>That vibe continues as I meet Easton. He’s friendly and dynamic, and his passion and enthusiasm for his work are immediately evident — I can see why Tony Robbins called him “the next Elon Musk.” (No pressure.) He shows me around the office and I get to see the history and future of Unlimited Tomorrow and — it seems likely — the entire prosthetics industry.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/easton-lachappelle-3.jpg" alt="Easton LaChappelle" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<hr />

<p><strong>Easton:</strong> This is the first prosthetic hand I made, back when I was 14 in Colorado. Lots of electrical tubing, fishing line as the tendons, servo motors, LEGO as plastic supports, Arudino board. I made my first printed circuit board — it’s funny looking back, I didn’t reverse it, so my name on it is spelled backwards.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/easton-lachappelle-4.jpg" alt="Easton LaChappelle" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Easton’s first prosthetic handAt the time this was just for fun, out of boredom. “How can I make something cool and interactive? How can I make something open-ended that isn’t just software and electronics, but is robotics and mechanics and systems design and all these things?” At the time, I was making a robotic hand that was controlled by a control glove. You might recognize this — it’s a Nintendo Power Glove that I bought off eBay. I cut off the whole forearm. This has flex sensors embedded within it.</p>

<p><strong>That’s such a great MacGyver hack, using an old Power Glove.</strong></p>

<p>It’s funny, the Power Glove didn’t catch on. They’re around $50 on eBay — it’s actually cheaper to buy a Power Glove than to buy five flex sensors. It was ahead of its time.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/easton-lachappelle-5.jpg" alt="Easton LaChappelle" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>You can see a natural progression. I stumbled upon a passion for creating things and turning ideas into reality, and I saw so many ways to improve on the original design. Adding an opposable thumb, individual finger joints, adding more motors, getting clever with software and electronics and the control systems behind it.</p>

<p>This is when <a href="https://www.makerbot.com/">MakerBot Industries</a> was really the only company in the consumer space. They had the old <a href="https://www.thingiverse.com/thing:457">CupCake</a>, the laser-cut 3D printers. I didn’t have one of these machines so I had to send a quote out, and I was getting quotes of $500 just to print a hand. Being 14 or 15 years old I didn’t have that kind of money, so I turned to social media and I found one of the early employees working at MakerBot who threw it on the printer one night, so I only had to pay for shipping.</p>

<p>As you can see, I still got clever with it, using rubber bands to help spring fingers back. I started working with aluminum, pretty much turning my bedroom into a lab. I’d work into the middle of the night.</p>

<p>1×</p>

<p>I grew up in a small town called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mancos,_Colorado">Mancos</a>, population of about 1,200 people. My graduating class was around 23 kids. I was bored a lot.</p>

<p><strong>So I’m guessing you didn’t have a 3D printing lab or anything.</strong></p>

<p>In a way I look back and it’s not great there was no support and no resources, but to its credit, it motivated me to go out and learn on my own. That’s how I found my passion and stumbled upon everything. I found the open source community which has always been an amazing knowledge base.</p>

<p>Growing up in Colorado, I started making these things and entering them into science fairs. In 2012, I met a small girl at a state science fair who was missing her right arm and was wearing a prosthetic device. It was the first time I saw this type of technology, and I got to talk to her and her parents about the process, how it was made, how much it cost. It completely blew me away — it was my “aha” moment.</p>

<p>It took months to create a prosthetic device for a growing child, and it cost $80,000. She was probably one of the few children to have this kind of device, and on top of that, it was a claw with one motion and a sensor. That really opened my eyes — I had a full robotic arm with individual fingers that could toss a ball and interact with people, and then she had this $80,000 claw… it’s night and day.</p>

<p>After I met her, I started making another arm that was a more prosthetic-centered design — it’s the left arm on that skeleton, with the glove on it. It’s more ergonomic, more organic-looking. This was my entry into muscle control and brainwave systems. I started using EEG headsets and sensors to control the device, and started increasing functionality across the board. That hand actually shook hands with President Obama at the White House science fair. It was a really amazing moment.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/easton-lachappelle-6.jpg" alt="Easton LaChappelle" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>That was my first taste of bigger systems design. This is around 2013, when Unlimited Tomorrow was being formed. Media started exploding — there was the White House science fair, I was doing an internship at NASA, I was traveling around doing keynotes. It was the craziest year of my life. I was around 17. I was invited to give a TEDx talk in Denver and Tony Robbins, who became our founding investor and partner, saw that and gave me a call one day, saying: “I can’t believe you’re still working out of your bedroom at your parents’ house. I need to help you take this to the next level.” He provided startup capital and some guidance and mentorship to help make that happen.</p>

<p>This was the first real prosthetic device that we made, for a 10-year-old girl named Momo. We did this <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/inculture/people-who-inspire/easton/">amazing documentary with Microsoft</a>. They helped out with a lot of this.</p>

<p>Microsoft gave me access to their secret R&amp;D lab. I had access to the best 3D printers in the world, and some engineering resources, to make all this happen. It really started validating our business model, which was sending a 3D scanner — at the time it was a webcam, actually — down to Florida where Momo lives. The first time I gave her this device was the first time I ever had a conversation with her and interacted with her in general. That was really validating — making a very personalized medical device for someone I’ve never even met or had a conversation with. That set the bar for us.</p>

<p>This is where we are today. Our current device is under a pound-and-a-half. Individual finger control, custom actuators, electronics, and batteries all in the palm of the hand. For a seven-year-old to a fifty-year-old, it’s all the same components — it’s all modular in that sense — and the forearm is basically empty. It links to a socket.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/easton-lachappelle-7.jpg" alt="Easton LaChappelle" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p><strong>You must know a decent amount about human physiology, then. You must have a sophisticated mental model of the arm.</strong></p>

<p>The human hand consistently blows me away, every day. It’s nearly impossible to truly replicate the human hand. It’s insane how it works.</p>

<p>We know the general shape and the function that we’re trying to achieve. Now how do we do that mechanically? Even to rotate your wrist, you have two bones that criss-cross. Trying to replicate that mechanically isn’t practical. You have to keep that in the back of your mind, but also invent new ways to maintain aesthetics.</p>

<p><em>Easton and I walk into the R&amp;D lab portion of the facility, where he shows me their industrial-grade 3D printers.</em></p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/easton-lachappelle-8.jpg" alt="Easton LaChappelle" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Almost everything you see here is 3D printed; these literally come off the machine looking just like this. It’s one thing to print something like this and keep it in a display case where no one can really touch it; it’s another thing to print something like this with the aesthetics and have it functional so you can give it to a child and they can play with it. You can see some of the accuracy of what we can print with — really crazy detail. We can print things already assembled, with pieces interlocked, such as fully-functional backpack buckles.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/easton-lachappelle-9.jpg" alt="Easton LaChappelle" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>The philosophy is, how can we send 1,000 arms to anywhere in the world, and someone can put it on and have a personalized result without a clinician being physically involved? That’s a really hard task, because up until now you would spend months with a clinician. We had to really take a step back, reinvent the technology, the delivery mechanism, and the whole business model. So we’re going direct to consumer while bringing in clinicians internally to make sure we’re staying ethical and safe. And then direct-to-consumer e-commerce, so an amputee can go to the website and fill out an eligibility form. If they’re eligible, they’re sent a 3D scanner, they take a 3D scan of the arm that they’re missing, take a scan of the full arm so we have a full image, match skin tone along the way.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/easton-lachappelle-10.jpg" alt="Easton LaChappelle" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>These are some of the iPads we use as 3D scanners. These are insane, for the cost — that was one big area that we were testing. Can someone’s parent who doesn’t know how to use a cellphone use this to 3D scan their child’s limb? Turns out they can! We’ve done a lot within the mobile app development to make that happen.</p>

<p>For us, it’s about accessibility and affordability. Affordability helps unlock accessibility.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/easton-lachappelle-11.jpg" alt="Easton LaChappelle" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p><strong>Being able to 3D print quickly and on-site… does that mean you’re able to move more of the process out of CAD software and into physical testing?</strong></p>

<p>Yeah. We 3D print something every night, whether it’s for production or R&amp;D. These machines let us stay nimble. You can fit a lot into these machines. It’s actually the same cost and time to print one bike pedal as it is to print 100 bike pedals.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/easton-lachappelle-12.jpg" alt="Easton LaChappelle" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p><strong>You’re almost moving to the zero-marginal-cost economics of digital products, but for physical products.</strong></p>

<p>Our inventory is mainly electronics and nuts-and-bolts; everything else is on-demand printed, and it’s fast enough that it allows us to do that. There’s very little inventory and overhead for what we do.</p>

<p>We can 3D print cages around things, so if we have a bunch of fingernails or other small pieces that get lost in the machine, we just 3D print cages around them so they come out together.</p>

<p>These are some disposable cages, so you can print fingernails in there and then cut away the cage after you take it out of the machine.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/easton-lachappelle-13.jpg" alt="Easton LaChappelle" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p><strong>How many people work at Unlimited Tomorrow?</strong></p>

<p>Twelve right now. We’re actively hiring about four other positions, and set to continue growing in 2020.</p>

<p>A really big piece of that is we have really amazing partnerships with HP, Microsoft… some of the CAD software we use is around $20,000 a seat, so we have a partnership with a company so we get that for free. That’s been really great.</p>

<p>We also have really solid marketing and storytelling, so when someone is talking about 3D printing and AI and all these different concepts, our products really help people to understand that.</p>

<p>We’re about 80% engineers right now, so we’re actively growing and actively hiring marketing staff to help us grow and take this to market. We’re looking to go to market early to mid 2020.</p>

<p><strong>Does it ever create challenges that you can’t test the devices yourself?</strong></p>

<p>Yes, and that’s why we’ve created a test group of 100 — we have a lot of children, adults, veterans, people from 15 different countries and all walks of life. It’s different if someone is born without an arm than if they lost an arm through an injury or disease. No two cases are the same. We’re trying to make universal technologies to solve those challenges and physical differences.</p>

<p>We also have wireless charging — you put this on the charger, and there’s a coil in the palm of the hand. We’ve been getting very creative with our mechanics.</p>

<p>1×</p>

<p><strong>How long does it last on a charge?</strong></p>

<p>That’s a really big piece. We were at a nonprofit conference a few months ago, and a lady came up to us saying, “I have a $120,000 prosthetic limb, but the battery just died.” It was 11 in the morning, and it was in her car — she wasn’t wearing it. The industry standard is a couple of hours. It’s awful. And it’s heavy as well — it’s like an old cellphone compared to the phones we have now.</p>

<p>We get a multi-day battery life. What sets us apart from anyone else in the industry is that we’ve created the whole solution from the ground up. Conventionally, one person makes the socket, one person makes the hand, one person makes the battery, the muscle sensors, and each of these components alone are a couple of thousand dollars. You get a really messy result that’s just a bad result for the patient. Half the people who have a device don’t wear them because of these problems — the adoption rate is horrible. We’re doing a lot to try and combine both worlds, function and aesthetics.</p>

<p>Our goal is to make this as affordable as possible and we are looking to launch our product for around $10,000. We also want to encourage growth in children so when they outgrow a device it will be even cheaper for them to get an upgrade.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/easton-lachappelle-14.jpg" alt="Easton LaChappelle" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p><strong>Why Rhinebeck? How did you wind up here?</strong></p>

<p>I was having a lot of challenges in Colorado. I’d moved up to the Fort Collins area, just north of Denver, with the hopes of being able to grow and expand. Before that I was in Southwest Corner; the nearest interstate was a couple of hundred miles away, I was very limited and having trouble finding a good core team and a commercial space where I could knock down walls and expand. Ultimately, I found some amazing commercial space, but I’d have to sign a 3-year lease, and would probably outgrow that space in 6 months. That was a major constraint.</p>

<p>Tony Robbins connected me with one of my mentors, <a href="https://twitter.com/JonathanPCohen?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Eauthor">Jonathan Cohen</a>. He actually owns this building, and the timing worked out beautifully. I was hitting my head against the wall trying to grow and expand a company where I was, and Jonathan said: “I just bought a 6,000 square foot building. You can have free rein.” We completely updated this building, tore up the carpet, polished the floors, it’s night and day from what it used to be. And proximity to New York City and the Boston area and MIT!</p>

<p>There have been an incredible amount of incentives from New York State that have helped us to grow and expand, from equipment purchases to R&amp;D credits to marketing opportunities. We’re becoming a poster child for the Hudson Valley retaining startups.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/easton-lachappelle-15.jpg" alt="Easton LaChappelle" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p><strong>What’s been your favorite thing about being based in the Hudson Valley?</strong></p>

<p>Growing up in Colorado, I love the combination of being able to go mountain biking or skiing, but then also being able to jump on a train and get to Penn Station in an hour-and-a-half. It’s the best of both worlds.</p>

<p>As we grow and look for talent, that’s all very helpful too.</p>

<p><strong>What have been some challenges of being located in the Hudson Valley?</strong></p>

<p>Not a lot. If anything, I think if we’d moved to a city there’d actually be less opportunity in terms of state financing options and grant opportunities. Because we’re in an area where IBM pulled out and really impacted the economy, there’s a lot of money set aside to help rejuvenate this area, and we fit into that.</p>

<p><strong>Outside of work, where in the Hudson Valley do you like to go?</strong></p>

<p>I live right outside of Kingston, nestled in the woods. I’m very close to Woodstock, which is a very fun place. Besides that, we always go up to the Catskills and venture down to Minnewaska State Park. There’s a lot to stay busy.</p>

<p><strong>What else would you want people to know?</strong></p>

<p>We’re a fast-growing company doing some incredible things, and we’re right around the corner from downtown Rhinebeck. You don’t have to be in a big hub like Silicon Valley to do these things. I want people to know that.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Tech" /><category term="Business" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[When he was just 14, Easton LaChappelle built his first working robotic arm out of fishing line, LEGO, and off-the-shelf electric tubing. The 10 years since then have been a whirlwind of activity, from showcasing his work to President Obama at the White House science fair, to getting seed funding from motivational speaker Tony Robbins, to starting his company Unlimited Tomorrow and moving it from Colorado to Rhinebeck.]]></summary></entry></feed>