<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-03-20T07:59:16-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Digital Terroir</title><subtitle>Exploring the intersection of software, culture, and place.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">My attempt to build software with a sense of place</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/my-attempt-to-build-software-with-a-sense-of-place/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My attempt to build software with a sense of place" /><published>2024-02-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-02-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/my-attempt-to-build-software-with-a-sense-of-place</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/my-attempt-to-build-software-with-a-sense-of-place/"><![CDATA[<p>I have a habit of embarking on very intense side projects that consume all my free time.</p>

<p>The first was Hudson Valley Talentbase — think Behance or Dribbble, but specifically for the Hudson Valley. The idea was strong, but ultimately lost momentum due to a truth that’s obvious in hindsight: a community built on people sharing their work will ultimately favor work that happens on a short timescale. If you’re a novelist and you write one book every two years, does that mean you only post once every two years? It’s hard to sustain a vibrant community built that way.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/talentbase.jpeg" alt="Hudson Valley Talentbase" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center">Hudson Valley Talentbase, back when I thought I could add some regional flavor by putting a map at the top of the page.</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>My second project like this was <a href="https://creativehudsonvalley.com">Creative Hudson Valley</a>, an online publication where I interviewed people doing interesting work in the region. This solved one problem but added another: on one hand, the additional editorial control meant that the site could showcase people doing the highest-quality work no matter the type or timeframe of output. On the other hand, it required substantial labor from me to keep it running.</p>

<p>My third project along these lines, after Hudson Valley Talentbase and Creative Hudson Valley were both sunsetted, is <a href="https://connecthv.com">ConnectHV</a>. It’s similar to Talentbase in that it’s a software product in which people can create their own profiles, but its approach is orthogonal to Talentbase’s — instead of focusing on the work, it focuses on the people.</p>

<p>Anyone with a Hudson Valley zip code can create a profile, upload some work, write some words, and make themselves publicly searchable. The database is rich enough that people can find each other easily: you can search for things like <strong>designers in Ulster County</strong> or <strong>filmmakers in Poughkeepsie</strong> and return a list of people who meet the criteria you’re looking for. I’ve spent a couple of years revising the value proposition, but the phrasing I’ve settled on is this: <strong>ConnectHV helps you to find your next coworker, contractor, cofounder, or creative collaborator.</strong></p>

<p>The common thread among all these projects, of course, is <strong>the Hudson Valley</strong>. It’s where I was born and raise and always planned to return. The Hudson Valley is large and spread out — in the 100-mile corridor between New York City and Albany, there are 11 counties and over 2 million residents.</p>

<p>The creative energy here is astounding, but it’s also hard for people to find one another. Let’s say you’re an engineer looking for a designer; if you live in a creative center like Manhattan or San Francisco, you can walk into the nearest Blue Bottle Coffee, throw a rock, and hit someone qualified to be your cofounder. Not so in a place as geographically diverse as the Hudson Valley.</p>

<p>We need a network that’s as distributed as our geography. We need <strong>an engine for fostering creative serendipity</strong>.</p>

<p>At least that’s my thesis. The communities in creative hotspots like Kingston, Beacon, and Poughkeepsie are already connected. But how do we build connections among those various communities, so that a filmmaker in Beacon can find a composer who lives in Rhinebeck, or a small business owner in Poughkeepsie can find a CFO-for-hire in Kingston?</p>

<p>That’s what I’m aiming for with ConnectHV.</p>

<h2 id="imbuing-software-with-a-sense-of-place">Imbuing software with a sense of place</h2>

<p>The easiest way to build a directory would’ve been to either use an off-the-shelf software product as-is, or to take some open-source platform like WordPress and theme it to be some approximation of what I wanted.</p>

<p>Neither of those approaches felt fully authentic to my vision, though. I’m a big believer in “eating your own dogfood” (or “drinking your own champagne,” as some prefer). If my goal is to showcase and connect the incredible work being done in the Hudson Valley, the platform itself should be incredible work done in the Hudson Valley.</p>

<p>So I decided to start from scratch. Every pixel and every line of code has been conceived from scratch in the Hudson Valley. By happy accident, even the underlying coding framework I’m using has Hudson Valley ties — Laravel, a PHP framework, was developed under the auspices of a Poughkeepsie-based company.</p>

<p>(A “coding framework” is a set of common functions and boilerplate conventions that abstract away common tasks, like interfacing with a database or rendering content to the screen. They enable developers to focus on the parts of their project that are unique, rather than those that are common to every software project.)</p>

<p>Even so, I’ve grappled with how to make ConnectHV an authentically Hudson Valley project.</p>

<h2 id="different-ways-of-understanding-software-with-a-sense-of-place">Different ways of understanding “software with a sense of place”</h2>

<p>The materials with which physical objects are made are imbued with specific geography. Rock and marble contains traces of the place it was brought out of the earth. Metals contain the story of their environment. Even the most abstract physical materials, such as plastic, can’t escape the fact that they were produced in a place out of raw materials that were produced in a place.</p>

<p>Food contains even more geography. Wine from different regions has completely different qualities, informed by the chemical content of the soil and the bacteria present in the place where it’s fermented. (This is the eponymous ”terroir” in “digital terroir.”)</p>

<p>Software has no such sense of geography. We speak in terms of pixels and code, but there are abstractions on top of the underlying reality: software is a series of instructions conveyed in 1s and 0s (really, billions of tiny switches being set to “on” or “off” inconceivably fast), resulting in electrons firing onto a flat surface to produce patterns of light.</p>

<p>Pixels don’t have a sense of place. They are not made of fibers produced from trees that grew in a particular forest; they are not written in ink whose origin can be traced.</p>

<p>Code doesn’t have a sense of place. It might have styles and conventions that are particular to the programmer, but not to the degree that literature from Russia differs from literature from Argentina. There are far fewer popular programming languages than spoken languages, and fewer ways to convey the same idea than in the written word.</p>

<h2 id="a-digression-does-software-really-need-to-have-a-sense-of-place">A digression: does software really need to have a sense of place?</h2>

<p>No, of course software doesn’t need a sense of place, any more than I want an iPhone made in one place to be different than an iPhone made in another place.</p>

<p>By day, I work on design systems at a large global company. “Design systems” are a way of keeping interfaces consistent and high-quality — essentially, a library of components and conventions that unify work done by various teams at the company.</p>

<p>Do we want the software our company makes to have regional variations, or even variations based on the personalities and preferences of its engineers and designers? No! Do we want our software that’s used by people all around the globe to feel rooted in a particular region, or should it have an approachable neutrality that makes it accessible to anyone anywhere?</p>

<p>In other words: <strong>the personality of software tends to come from the software itself, without being informed by its place of origin, because <em>software doesn’t really have a place of origin</em></strong>. Its “place of origin” is the web — it’s built out of non-regional raw materials by people whose skills are aggregated from forbearers all around the world developing a common “digital production” culture with little regard for borders, answering Stack Overflow questions from people halfway across the world and learning from blog posts written anywhere and everywhere.</p>

<h2 id="three-takes-on-a-sense-of-place-for-software">Three takes on “a sense of place” for software</h2>

<p>In my current thinking, there are three possible ways that software can have a sense of place:</p>

<h3 id="-the-superficial-way">💅 The superficial way</h3>

<p><strong>The software is non-regional, but it has a regional ”coat of paint.”</strong> This is the most obvious, least satisfying, interpretation of digital terroir. The website for the New York State DMV feels like a New York website because it has a little picture of New York State on it. If you swapped out that picture for a picture of Montana, though, would anyone be able to tell it wasn’t actually a website from Montana?</p>

<h3 id="-the-foundational-way">🧱 The foundational way</h3>

<p><strong>The underpinnings of the software are regional.</strong> Theoretically, if the software were written in some regional style using a regional programming paradigm (is there such a thing?) and design language (there is such a thing, but just barely), it would feel like the place where it was written. I suspect it would feel forced, though, and perhaps unnoticeable to most observers.</p>

<h3 id="-the-realistic-way">🌱 The realistic way</h3>

<p><strong>We imbue the design and content of the software with regional characteristics, while acknowledging that software itself might not have regional characteristics at the foundational level.</strong></p>

<p>This is the version that seems most realistic to me right now. I don’t know that I can imbue ConnectHV’s code with Hudson Valley flavor, but I can nod to the Hudson Valley through the design and content of the site. I can put some of my own values, informed by three decades of life in the Hudson Valley, into the site, both consciously and unconsciously. I can nudge users towards behaviors that align with Hudson Valley attitudes and folkways. I can imbue the site with regional design reinforced by responsible code.</p>

<p>I suppose this is all reliant on understanding what makes a place feel like that place. In the original ”Digital Terroir” talk I gave at <a href="https://youtu.be/XUtUYKuSPpY?si=L8_YSFc1oj6bgpm8&amp;ref=digitalterroir.org">CatskillsConf 2018</a>, I phrased it like this:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>When I think of the Hudson Valley, I think of places like the Ashokan Center. I think of towns like New Paltz and Beacon and Rhinebeck, which each have their own personality but still share the values of the Hudson Valley. I think of the places to hike, and the places to eat, and the farmers’ markets and independent stores.</p>
</blockquote>

<blockquote>
  <p>The Hudson Valley is about small farms, slow food, and good neighbors. It’s about doing good work, but avoiding the mentality of “growth at all costs.” The pace is a little slower here than in New York City, but thanks to the easy train access, we still have the cultural benefits.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>And what does this look like, practically? Again from 2018:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The things we make can be imbued with the character of the Hudson Valley. We can make software with breathing room, both in the design and in the user behavior it encourages. We can reject the idea of “growth at all costs” and instead build products that promote our users’ wellbeing. We can design and program things in a way that respects work-life balance, and helps people to thrive, for no other reason except that they’re people, and people have infinite worth. We can make software that shares our values, knowing that our values are influenced by the place that we’re planted.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I don’t find that answer satisfying anymore. I don’t know that I did then, either, but a conference talk needs an ending that sounds nice. The truth is, that description could apply to lots of places, not just the Hudson Valley.</p>

<p>And so I’m left with a lead on what it looks like to imbue ConnectHV with the spirit of the Hudson Valley, but still more questions than answers.</p>

<p>Here’s what I need to pursue:</p>

<ol>
  <li>What makes a place feel like a place?</li>
  <li>What makes certain places feel “thick“ — lived in, organic, historic — and other places feel “thin” — superficial, unrooted, transient?</li>
  <li>What makes software distinctive from other media? How do other media find themselves rooted in a place-and-time (how could anyone but Kerouac write Kerouac? Or anyone but Dostoevsky write Dostoevsky?), and how does that manifest with software?</li>
</ol>

<p>And, perhaps most importantly: should we want any software to have a sense of place, or do we want it to be completely transparent so we can use it quickly and then get back to our lives?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How my Hudson Valley projects have gotten me thinking about how to imbue software with local flavor.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Digital terroir and media ecology</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/digital-terroir-and-media-ecology/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Digital terroir and media ecology" /><published>2024-02-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-02-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/digital-terroir-and-media-ecology</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/digital-terroir-and-media-ecology/"><![CDATA[<p>In college, I took a fascinating class called Media Ecology. If you know anything about media ecology, it’s probably Marshall McLuhan’s famous line, “the medium is the message.” If you don’t know anything about media ecology… well, you’re probably more fun at parties than I am.</p>

<p>Media ecology is the study of how the media environment shapes the way we perceive the world. The ideas that stuck with me from college include:</p>

<ul>
  <li>“You can’t use a hammer without getting a callous” — we can’t use any technology without finding ourselves changed by it.</li>
  <li>Any technology is an extension of some existing human faculty. A wrench extends our arms; written language extends our memory; clothing extends our skin.</li>
  <li>A medium can’t be neutral. The same idea presented in a book, a podcast, and a TV show is not the same idea at all — it’s colored by the biases and predispositions of its delivery mechanism.</li>
  <li>It’s a lot easier to focus on the content than the medium, for the same reason it’s hard for a fish to understand what it means to be wet.</li>
</ul>

<p>The thing about media ecology is that it changes the way you think. It becomes hard to see the world in any other way; you turn on the TV and you’re just as aware of the quick cuts and editorial tricks as the content itself. You wander into a mall and find yourself noticing how the architecture nudges you towards different behaviors than, say, a commercial district.</p>

<p>I’m not an expert in media ecology — I’ve barely read anything on the subject since college, and haven’t gone much deeper than its most popular practitioners like Marshall McLuhan and Neil Postman. But I keep thinking of it as I mull over ideas about digital terroir.</p>

<p>A media ecologist would ask: what biases and assumptions are baked into software as a medium, regardless of the content? Does software naturally push you to think bigger and more globally? Does it encourage you to reframe your thinking in binary ways, flattening complex thoughts into a form palatable to a machine? Does it discourage specificity and nudge you towards thinking in terms of millions and billions instead of dozens and hundreds?</p>

<p>Perhaps yes. But honestly, I’m not even sure what the “medium” we’re talking about is.</p>

<p>Consider an Instagram post. Is the medium:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Photography</li>
  <li>Software</li>
  <li>The smartphone</li>
  <li>The Internet</li>
  <li>The algorithmic feed</li>
  <li>Instagram</li>
</ul>

<p>You could make a case for each of these, and I suspect the answer is “all of the above.”</p>

<p>Are any of these media conducive to cultivating a sense of place? Or, to personalize it for myself: if I want to build tools that connect and reinforce the community in the Hudson Valley, are any of these media suitable, or will my efforts be undercut by the medium itself?</p>

<p>I’m starting to dual-track my investigation into these ideas. I’m going to read (or re-read) some works on both media ecology and the idea of “place.” I’m starting to put together an informal Digital Terroir reading list, which I’ll share when it’s in a presentable form. And I’m continuing to work on <a href="https://connecthv.com">ConnectHV</a> while trying to keep these ideas in mind.</p>

<p><em>(Of course, I’m doing all this while working hard at my day job and being a hands-on dad, so no promises about the timeline.)</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The field of media ecology can inform how we think about using software to reinforce a sense of place.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What do I mean by “software with a sense of place?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/software-with-a-sense-of-place/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What do I mean by “software with a sense of place?" /><published>2024-02-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-02-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/software-with-a-sense-of-place</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/software-with-a-sense-of-place/"><![CDATA[<p>There are two possible meanings to “software with a sense of place:”</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Software that feels like a physical location.</strong> The best example of this would be a social video game, like World of Warcraft or Final Fantasy XIV, which immerses the player into a constructed world.</li>
  <li><strong>Software that feels rooted in the place where it was made.</strong></li>
</ol>

<p>This second meaning is the one I intended.</p>

<p>In the culinary world, “terroir” is the idea that things taste like the place in which they were produced. Wine from France tastes different than wine from California; cheese made in one place doesn’t taste like cheese made in another place.</p>

<p>There are cultural reasons for this, but there are physical reasons too. The nutrient composition of the soil in which grapes are grown, or the bacteria and fungi floating around in the air where cheese is produced, directly impact the flavor.</p>

<p>What I’m particularly interested in exploring is whether we can invest software with this same principle. What would it mean to have an app that felt truly rooted in the place where it was made.</p>

<p>There are blunt versions of this — famously, Japanese web design tends to look very different from almost anywhere else. But in general, everything on the internet tends to move towards the same aesthetic mean.</p>

<p>I can think of several reasons why this might be true:</p>

<ol>
  <li>The medium itself nudges software in the same aesthetic direction. (”The medium” in this case being pixels, code, screens, the internet, or some combination of all those).</li>
  <li>Since software itself is a recent invention, it developed in a more globalized world than many other media. Perhaps this gives it a tendency towards a more homogeneous design.</li>
  <li>Copycat design, or even just designers being influenced by other designers, leads to convergence on a common design language.
    <ol>
      <li>This could also be a case of companies wanting to be similar to companies they admire or view as successful.</li>
      <li>This is supported by the emergence of certain design trends — after Stripe becomes well-known for good design, lots companies suddenly have websites that look like Stripe’s; after Linear becomes popular, lots of companies suddenly have websites that look like Linear’s; etc.</li>
    </ol>
  </li>
  <li>A disproportionate amount of software comes from the same handful of places, so a disproportionate amount of software has that same “Bay Area style.” As new software begins to emulate existing software, or new designers emulate experienced designers, this becomes the “house style” of the web.</li>
</ol>

<p>I should be clear that I don’t think a generic, homogeneous design language is necessarily a bad thing, or that ”software with a sense of place” is necessarily a good thing.</p>

<p>That is, I don’t think there’s a moral requirement that software should reflect the place that it’s made. A company that makes enterprise software for Fortune 500s worldwide probably doesn’t want to look too specific to a particular region.</p>

<p>However, I think that we lose something if everything we consume online is divorced from a sense of place. Our content is becoming more general — just try to find a local newspaper that’s really thriving — and the buckets in which that content is distributed is becoming more general too. (How many local newspapers are just re-skinned versions of USA Today?)</p>

<p>As I develop my own side project, which is designed specifically for people in the Hudson Valley, I‘m thinking more and more about what it would mean for it to truly be a Hudson Valley website. Bits aren’t influenced by their environment of origin the way that atoms are. How can I imbue ConnectHV with a deep, authentic sense of rootedness?</p>

<p>What even is “a sense of place?”</p>

<p>More on that next time.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Can software feel rooted in the place where it was made?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Digital Terroir at CatskillsConf</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/digital-terroir-catskillsconf-2018/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Digital Terroir at CatskillsConf" /><published>2024-02-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-02-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/digital-terroir-catskillsconf-2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/digital-terroir-catskillsconf-2018/"><![CDATA[<p><em>“Digital Terroir” began as a conference talk that I gave in October 2018 at CatskillsConf, a tech conference in the woods of the Hudson Valley. Some of the content is outdated now, and my thinking on much of this has evolved, but it remains an excellent primer into the sort of things I want to talk about on this site.</em></p>

<hr />

<p>How many of you have ever been to, or ever seen, a coffee shop that looks anything like this?</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/digitalterroir-coffee.jpeg" alt="A generic coffee shop" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>You know the one I’m talking about. It’s probably got white walls with some artwork on it, reclaimed wood somewhere, concrete floors or something else similarly industrial chic. They all have the same smell — coffee, predictably enough.</p>

<p>I think everyone’s been to a coffee shop like this. And it’s not surprising, because these things are everywhere.</p>

<p>I’m not talking about Starbucks, where it’s a chain, but coffee shops that have independently developed this same hipster coffee shop aesthetic.</p>

<p>You can find these in New York; you can find them in San Francisco. They’re in Chicago and Dallas and Detroit. You can find them in Sydney, Singapore, Dubai, Frankfurt.</p>

<p>I’d call it an epidemic, except I actually love coffee shops like this. They have great music and great coffee. The baristas have great beards.</p>

<p>But the world is getting flatter. Our culture seems to be compressing, regressing to the aesthetic mean. It’s easier and easier to find things that look the same, no matter where you go. Not just in terms of Wal-Mart being everywhere, but in terms of things that are totally independent and would’ve previously had their own personality, don’t really have their own personality anymore.</p>

<p>But we’ll get back to that.</p>

<p>I haven’t introduced myself yet, have I? I’m a designer and programmer, and I make apps and websites for a living. I’ve had the privilege to work with a variety of companies and clients, from independent creatives to startups to global megacorporations. So today I’m here to talk to you about… wine.</p>

<p>Well, not wine exactly. I know almost nothing about wine. But something tangentially related to wine. I’m here to talk to you about terroir.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/digitalterroir-terroir.jpeg" alt="Terroir" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Terroir is the idea that wines made in different places will taste like that place; they’ll assume the characteristics of the geography and culture in which they were produced.</p>

<p>Wines made in Bordeaux, taste like Bordeaux. Wines made in Napa, taste like Napa.</p>

<p>It makes sense, doesn’t it? Wine comes from grapes, grapes are grown in the ground, so the growing conditions of the grapes will influence the taste of the wine. Things like climate — the precipitation and temperature the grapes were subject to. Even the nutrient composition of the soil will alter the taste of the wine.</p>

<p>But terroir is deeper than that. The local bacteria will impact the taste of the wine. Different places have different strains of bacteria floating around in the air, and present in the soil. Those bacteria will alter the growth of the grapes, and involve themselves in the fermentation of the wine. You could say that the essence of the place imbues itself into the wine.</p>

<p>And so wine is the product of the bacterial culture in the environment, but it’s also the product of the human culture of the environment. Wine is cultivated by a vintner — a winemaker — and so that winemaker’s instincts and methods, their approach to making wine, greatly affects the resulting wine. The winemaking culture in which they were trained will imprint itself on the wine.</p>

<p>You can take identical grapes and make wine using the same recipe in two different places, and those wines will not be the same. That’s terroir.</p>

<p>Other things besides wine have terroir.</p>

<p>Beer has terroir. There are varieties of beer that are fermented in open air, allowing any local flora and fauna to fall in and influence the flavor. Coffee has terroir, tobacco has terroir, and cannabis has terroir. Cheese has terroir. Even vidalia onions have terroir.</p>

<p>I think we can expand this into a more general principle:</p>

<p>The things we make are imbued with the character of the places in which they were made, and the people who made them.</p>

<p>Music takes on the character of the place and time in which it was written. Writing can’t help but be part of an oeuvre. British film feels different than American film feels different than Japanese film or French film. New York pizza tastes better than any other pizza on earth (come at me, Chicago.)</p>

<p>Anything handcrafted, whether it’s wine or cheese or furniture, has terroir.</p>

<p>The things we make feel like the places where they were made. And, moreover, they are imbued with the character and personality and culture of the people who made them.</p>

<p>I’ve been thinking about this idea a lot lately. Being a designer and developer, I wonder: do digital artifacts also have terroir? Obviously they wouldn’t be impacted by the bacterial environment or the precipitation in which we code a website, but does the culture and gestalt of a place impact the websites and apps made there?</p>

<p>I had big plans for this talk. I was going to get screenshots of websites from all over — Russian websites and Indian websites and Japanese websites and French websites, and websites from different cities in the US — and put them up on the screen, and triumphantly declare: “Yes, software does have terroir!”</p>

<p>But instead I found… this.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/digitalterroir-nope.jpeg" alt="Nope" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Everything looks the same! It’s not just that everything shares the similar, Bootstrappy layout — full-width header image, center column of text, blocky layout — but that everything looks like it’s trying to copy the same sites. Everything’s trying to look like Stripe or Medium. Everyone’s looking at the same inspirations on Dribbble and copying the same code snippets from Stack Overflow.</p>

<p>This isn’t meant to sound like an indictment of similar work, by the way. It’s not wrong that the whole English-speaking Web seems to have coalesced around the same limited sets of layouts. It makes sense that websites should have a common vocabulary, so users don’t have to relearn the interface every time they visit a new website. It makes sense that apps use the same set of UI conventions, or that every piece of desktop software doesn’t look vastly different than its peers.</p>

<p>It’s not wrong, but as someone who likes the world to have some character, it is kind of disappointing.</p>

<p>For the first time in history, we have instant access to things made in places all around the world. And for the first time in history, things made in those places all look exactly the same.</p>

<p>It makes sense. A startup in Mumbai isn’t just competing against other startups in Mumbai, it’s competing against startups halfway around the world. Websites and apps aren’t really aimed at a local audience, they’re aimed at a global audience, so the place they’re trying to feel like is just: Earth.</p>

<p>But I can’t help but feel like the world would be richer if the digital products we build were imbued with a sense of the place in which they were built, and the people who built them.</p>

<p>And so we’re back to the beginning: the world is getting flatter.</p>

<p>There was a time when you could drive coast-to-coast across the United States, and if you kept your radio on, you’d hear different things in different cities. Let’s say you started in Kingston, New York — you’d hear a Kingston radio station, with music selected by a Kingston DJ. As you’d drive, Kingston would go out of range, and a new radio station would fade in. You’d hear music selected by a Pittsburgh DJ, probably with some local flavor mixed in. You’d keep going and hear different music in Saint Louis, and Detroit, and eventually California.</p>

<p>Each place would’ve had its own sound, and in addition to the geographic place-building happening in your head, you’d be building a cultural map as well.</p>

<p>If you try that again today, you’ll find something very different. There are pockets of independent radio, of course, but by-and-large you’ll find the same thing in every city. Pittsburgh? IHeartRadio with Spyder Harrison, playing some Taylor Swift. Saint Louis? IHeartRadio with Spyder Harrison, playing some Taylor Swift. Detroit? IHeartRadio with Spyder Harrison, playing some Taylor Swift. California? Well, probably some M83 or something, but you get the drift.</p>

<p>Am I romanticizing a little to make a point? Yes, absolutely. Maybe we never lived in a utopian world of local DJs with impeccable, geographically-informed taste. Then again, maybe it’s just hard to remember a time before demographic data ruled every decision and “mainstream taste” was defined as whatever the most people find inoffensive.</p>

<p>That’s where we are now. Lots of coffee shops that look the same, because Instagram can bring in foot traffic, and this is the style that gets lots of likes on Instagram.</p>

<p>Popular fashion that looks the same, because it gets lots of pins on Pinterest.</p>

<p>Places and things in the physical world optimized for algorithmic engagement, where the only thing that matters is that they are similar to other things that have gotten lots of engagement.</p>

<p>One of the great promises of the Internet was that anyone could find their tribe. We’d no longer be bound by whatever suited mainstream culture — we could watch shows that would never find an audience on TV, and find songs that would never get played on the radio, and meet people who shared the same obscure, esoteric hobbies.</p>

<p>And yes, that happened, to a point. But as the long tail got longer, the mainstream got flatter. What was local, got more local; what was global, went more global.</p>

<p>And so the culture flattens towards a unified, global aesthetic; a pleasant mediocrity is favored above distinctive personality. It’s better to have something that a lot of people kind of like, than something that a few people love and a few people hate.</p>

<p>“Algorithms are great at giving you something you like, but terrible at giving you something you love.” — David Perell</p>

<p>In agriculture, there’s the concept of “monoculture.”</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/digitalterroir-monoculture.jpeg" alt="Monoculture" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>In traditional farming, a single plot of land would support several types of crops. These crops would be rotated seasonally and annually, and because different crops take different nutrients from the ground, this would ensure that the soil never got worn out. Rotating crops actually strengthens the soil.</p>

<p>With industrial farming, however, came the rise of monoculture. Huge swaths of land are planted with the same crop, season after season and year after year. It’s more economical to do things this way when producing food for a huge market, but it wears out the soil. Farms need to add chemicals to the soil to replenish the depleted nutrients, making things less natural and less environmentally sound.</p>

<p>Monoculture is fragile, too. If you grow multiple types of crops in a year and one crop is hit with blight, you won’t lose everything. If you only grow one thing and it gets wiped out, though, you’re done.</p>

<p>Our culture right now is a monoculture.</p>

<p>I’m not saying that the Internet will one day get struck with a blight and suddenly all the Bootstrap websites will go away. I am saying that it’s all just a little… boring.</p>

<p>The Internet is the predominant culture-making force in our society. Want to learn something new? You go to the Internet. Looking for entertainment? Go to the Internet. Need to shop for something? Go to the Internet. As the Internet goes, society goes also.</p>

<p>The movies we watch, the books we read, the clothes we wear, the products we buy — all suggested to us by algorithms. The Internet keeps giving us more of what it thinks we want, based on the aggregated taste of people just like us. We’re trapped in an echo chamber of our own making.</p>

<p>This is the part of the talk where you start tuning me out, because I sound like I’m getting all doom-and-gloom about the present and romanticizing the past. I promise that’s not where I’m going with this!</p>

<p>Where I’m going is here:</p>

<p>Let’s say we’re all agreed that the world would be a richer, more vibrant place if our digital artifacts had a sense of place, like our physical ones. How would we go about doing that? How would we go about encouraging <em>terroir</em> in the things we make?</p>

<p>We should start by considering the character and personality of the places we inhabit. For me, that’s the Hudson Valley.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/digitalterroir-hv.jpeg" alt="Hudson Valley" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center"></figcaption>
</figure>

<p>When I think of the Hudson Valley, I think of places like the Ashokan Center. I think of towns like New Paltz and Beacon and Rhinebeck, which each have their own personality but still share the values of the Hudson Valley. I think of the places to hike, and the places to eat, and the farmers’ markets and independent stores.</p>

<p>The Hudson Valley is about small farms, slow food, and good neighbors. It’s about doing good work, but avoiding the mentality of “growth at all costs.” The pace is a little slower here than in New York City, but thanks to the easy train access, we still have the cultural benefits.</p>

<p>Wherever you’re from, you know that place’s character and personality. And you can express that character and personality through your work.</p>

<p>For the Hudson Valley, that might mean a few different things:</p>

<p>On the superficial level, we could make color and typographic choices that reflect the environment. Use colors that are present in the local environment, typography that’s authentic to the history of the Hudson Valley, etc. We can even go so far as to use visual forms that reflect the geography of the region.</p>

<p>But all this sounds a little contrived, doesn’t it? You can’t just tell a client, “I’m going to use lots of greens and blues, even though those aren’t your brand colors. And I refuse to use Helvetica, because that’s a Swiss font, and this isn’t Switzerland.”</p>

<p>No, we have to go deeper than that. Just like with terroir — it doesn’t hit you over the head, but it’s the subtle undercurrent. The things we make can be imbued with the character of the Hudson Valley. We can make software with breathing room, both in the design and in the user behavior it encourages. We can reject the idea of “growth at all costs” and instead build products that promote our users’ wellbeing. We can design and program things in a way that respects work-life balance, and helps people to thrive, for no other reason except that they’re people, and people have infinite worth. We can make software that shares our values, knowing that our values are influenced by the place that we’re planted.</p>

<p>I can’t tell you what terroir looks like for you. I don’t know your place as intimately as you do, and I don’t know how it might express itself through your work. Honestly, these are just ideas that I’ve been chewing on, and I don’t have any final conclusions yet.</p>

<p>But that’s a poor way to end a talk, so what I can tell you is this: If you consider terroir and consider the character and outlook that you’re putting into your work, the world can be a richer and more vibrant place. Our corner of the Internet can start unflattening, and gain more character. It might start to feel a little more like the early days, when the Web was wonderful and weird.</p>

<p>I never told you the literal translation of “terroir,” did I? It’s a French word that means “of the earth.”</p>

<p>Isn’t that perfect? “Of the earth.”</p>

<p>Just because we build digital products doesn’t mean they can’t be rooted and grounded in the soil beneath our feet.</p>

<figure>
  <img src="http://localhost:4000/assets/img/digitalterroir-thanks.jpeg" alt="Thanks" class="w-full" />
  <figcaption class="font-sans text-center">Neither of these "current projects" are current now (they were in 2018).</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Neither of these “current projects” are current now (they were in 2018).
Thank you.</p>

<p>Resources
Style is an Algorithm (Racked)
The Algorithmic Trap (David Perell)
Why Japanese Web Design is So Different (Randomwire)</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The original conference talk I gave about Digital Terroir introduced many of the ideas I'm still thinking about, from software & place to the dangers of monoculture.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Digital Terroir</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-digital-terroir/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Digital Terroir" /><published>2024-02-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-02-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-digital-terroir</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-digital-terroir/"><![CDATA[<p><em>Digital Terroir</em> began as a conference talk. In 2018, I was working at an AgTech company and reading plenty of Michael Pollan, and the agriculture concepts I was exposed to began swirling with my deep love of the Hudson Valley (my lifelong home) and my interest in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Media_ecology?ref=digitalterroir.org">media ecology</a> (which I dove into, quite pretentiously, in college).</p>

<p>By day, I’m a product designer and engineer at a San Francisco tech company, working remotely from my home base near the Hudson River. By night, I’m a chronic tinkerer who’s always working on side projects.</p>

<p>I’ve been considering the thread that unifies all my side projects:</p>

<ol>
  <li>There was “Hudson Valley Talentbase,” a Dribbble-like network for people in the region to upload the interesting projects they were working on, in the hopes of driving creative collaboration.</li>
  <li>There was <a href="https://creativehudsonvalley.com">Creative Hudson Valley</a>, an online publication where I interviewed creatives doing interesting work here.</li>
  <li>Now there’s <a href="https://connecthv.com">ConnectHV</a>, an online directly of creatives and professionals in the Hudson Valley.</li>
</ol>

<p>The theme is obvious when I write it out, but — beyond “stuff for the Hudson Valley” — my real interest is in <em><strong>software that reinforces a sense of place</strong></em>.</p>

<p>In other words, digital terroir.</p>

<p>The grain of the internet is to drive everything towards growth: bigger, faster, flatter, more global. I’m interested in ways we can use the internet to go the other way: more local, more flavorful, more specific, more niche.</p>

<p>This newsletter/website will be where I explore these ideas in public. Sometimes I’ll write broadly, about the concepts themselves; other times I’ll write about something specific I’m working on, such as behind-the-scenes of my Hudson Valley side projects. Occasionally, I intend to review or respond to some book or article that seems relevant.</p>

<p>If you’re interested in following along, you can subscribe via email or your <a href="https://feedbin.com/?ref=digitalterroir.org">RSS reader</a>. I always appreciate feedback and discussion, so don’t hesitate to reach out with any thoughts you have.</p>

<p>I look forward to exploring and learning, together, out loud.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Is it possible to build software that respects and reinforces a “sense of place,” rather than regressing to some placeless, generic style?]]></summary></entry></feed>